[Man] Our Father, who art in heaven, hallowed be Thy name.
در ما  والاي بهشتي  نامت مقدس باد
Thy kingdom come, Thy will be done,
ادشاهيت محقق ميشود و ميآيد
on earth as it is in heaven.
در زمين همانند بهشت
Give us this day our daily bread,
روزي ما را برسان و
and forgive us our trespasses,
خطاهايمان را ببخش
as we forgive those who trespass against us.
همنانکه ما خطاهاي ديران را
And lead us not into temptation,
ما را از وسوسه هاي شيطاني
but deliver us from evil.
در امان دار
For Thine is the kingdom, the power...
ادشاهي از آن توست   قدرت
and the glory now and forever.
و شکوه   اکنون و همواره
- Amen. - [All] Amen.
آمين
Thank you, Father Macklepenny,
ممنون  در مکلني
for coming all the way across town to be our guest speaker.
براي قدم رنجه تا شهر بعنوان سخنران مهمان
[Man's Voice] When I raise my flashing sword...
وقتي شمشير درخشانم را بالا ميبرم
and my hand takes hold on judgment,
و عدالت با دستانم جاري ميشود
I will take vengeance upon mine enemies.
انتقامم را از دشمنانم مييرم
And I will repay those who haze me.
و آزارشان را تلافي ميکنم
O Lord, raise me to Thy right hand...
خدايا   مرا به نيابت خودت بالا ببر
and count me among Thy saints.
و مرا از رهيزکارانت بشمار
And I am reminded on this holy day...
ومن در اين روز مقدس يادآور ميشم
of the sad story of Kitty Genovese.
ماجراي اندوهناک کيتي جنوويسه رو
As you all may remember,
همتون بخاطر دارين
a long time ago, almost 30 years ago,
خيلي وقت يش   حدودا 30 سال
this poor soul cried out for help...
اين روح بينوا التماس کمک ميکرد
time and time again,
بارها وبارها
but no person answered her calls.
ولي هيکس باو اسخي نداد
Though many saw,
ره خيلي ها ديدند
no one so much as called the police.
هيکس ليسو خبر نکرد
They all just watched as Kitty was being stabbed to death...
اونا فقط زخمي شدن تا مرشو تماشا کردن
in broad daylight.
در روز روشن
They watched as her assailant walked away.
اونا درحاليکه مهاجم قدم زنان ميرفت تماشا ميکردن
Now, we must all fear evil men.
حالا  ما بايد از مردان شيطاني بترسيم
But there is another kind of evil...
ولي شيطان ديري هست
which we must fear most,
که ما بايد بيشتر بترسيم
and that is the indifference...
و اون بيتفاوتي
of good men!
به مردان خوبه
I do believe the monsignor's finally got the point.
من معتقدم بالاخره اسقف موضوعو ميفهمه
Aye.
آره
[Man] Hey, Connor!
هي  کانر
What?
يه؟
Yeah! Who's the master?
هي رئيس کيه؟
You're gonna be training her today.
ميخواي ازش ياد بيري
Aye.
آره
- Basically, the rule of thumb here is... - Wait. Rule of thumb?
اصولا   قانون شست اينجاست وايسا. قانون شست؟
In the early 1900s, it was legal for men to beat their wives...
اوايل 1900 مردا مجاز بودن زناشونو بزنن
as long as they used a stick no wider than their thumb.
اه وبي کوتاهتر از شستشون داشتن
Can't do much damage with that then, can we?
اونجوري نميتونيم خوب بزنيم ميتونيم؟
Perhaps it should've been the "rule of wrist."
شايد اون قانون م بوده
I knew you two pricks would give me problems.
ميدونم شماها مشکل سازين
Come on. It's St. Patty's Day. It's all in good fun.
هي.امروز عيد اتريکه همش خوشيه
Ah, fuck you! And fuck you too!
تف بذاتت و تف بذات تو
We're sorry, all right? Just-Just relax.
متاسفيم باشه؟ حالا راحت باش
Oh, shit.
اوه  واي
Hey, fuck-ass, give me a beer.
هي  کوني  يه آبجو بده
Listen, boys, I've got some very bad news.
وش کنين  سرا  خبراي بدي دارم
I'm gonna have to close down t-t-the bar.
ميخوام ميکده رو ببندم
The Russians are buying up buildings all over the town, includin' this one.
روسها شهرو تماما خريدن ازجمله اينجا
Fuck! Ass!
لعنت  الاغ
And they're not lettin' me renew my lease.
و نميذارن من کرايمو تجديد کنم
- [Disgruntled Chattering] - Let me talk to my boss.
بذار با رئيسم حرف بزنم
- Maybe he can do something. - What the fuck's your boss gonna do?
شايد کاري کنه رئيست ه غلطي ميتونه بکنه؟
Listen, fellas, I don't want anyone to know.
وش کنين  بيوجودا نميخوام
So you keep your traps shut!
هيکي بدونه  س بارتونو ببندين
You know what they say: People in glass houses sink s-s-ships.
:ميدونين ي فتن مردم رمخونه کشتيا رو غرق ميکنن
Hey, Doc, I gotta buy you, like, a proverb book or somethin'.
هي  دکتر  يه ندنامه احتياج داري
This mix-and-match shit has gotta go.
اين آشغالدوني کارش تمومه
- [Laughter] - What?
ي؟
A penny saved is worth two in the bush, isn't it?
سيلي نقد به از حلواي نسيه است
And don't cross the road if you can't get out of the kitchen.
و اه راهو ياد نداري تو خونت بمون
What's this, then?
اين يه ديه؟
I am Ivan Checkov, and you will be closing now.
من ايوان کوفم و شما الان بايد ببندين
Checkov.
کوف
Well, this here's McCoy. We find a Spock, we've got us an away team.
اين مک کويه  ما يه شبح داريم ما کاري بکسي نداريم
Me in no mood for discussion. You, you stay.
من حوصله بحث ندارم  تو تو بمونين بقيتون  يالا برين
The rest of you, go now.
را ي کارتون نميرينو
Why don't you make like a tree and get the fuck out of here!
و ورتونو م نميکنين
You know he's got till the week's end, right?
اون تا آخر هفته ميره.  ها؟
You don't have to be hard-asses, do ya?
نبايد يوبس باشين  مه نه؟
- It's St. Patty's Day. Everyone's Irish tonight. - Mmm.
عيد اتريکه  همه امشب ايرلندين
Why don't you just pull up a stool and have a drink with us?
را نمياين با هم بنوشيم؟
- This is no game! If you won't go, - [Glass Shattering]
بازي نداريم  اه نميخواين برين
We will make you go.
مجبورتون ميکنيم
So these two guys are kickin' the shit out of each other, right?
س اين دوتا سر داشتن تو
This guy picks up an old kitchen sink or something...
سر وکله هم ميزدن  ها؟
and fuckin'crushes this guy with it.
با يه وان قديمي
It makes a big bang. [Continues, Indistinct]
ميکوبه تو کله لعنتي
Look at him. His spine's all crushed. Had to be one big motherfucker.
يه انفجار بزر
Huge. Three, four hundred pounds. Fuckin'huge.
غول.سيصد هارصد وند غول لعنتي
- That's pretty thin. - Very thin.
خيلي لاغره   خيلي
[Man] Okay. All right, all right.
بسيار خوب
Say these two guys right here, they don't even know the fuckin'huge guy.
بو اين دو تا همديرو نميشناختن
They're just staggering home from a bar still all fucked up from St. Patty's last night.
اونا تمام شب اتريک مقدسو از خونه تا ميکده ول ميشتن
They decide to take a shortcut down through the alley.
اونا ميخواستن از کوه ميونبر بزنن
Wrong fuckin' alley, huh?
کوه لعنتي غلط  ها؟
'Cause this big motherfucker, he's just waitin' for 'em, right?
اون مادرجنده غول منتظرشون بوده  ها؟
And what could be more perfect for a strong-arm robbery? Two drunk guys all bandaged up.
و واسه يه دزد غول ي بهتر؟  دو تا مست باندي
They're already injured, for Christ's sakes. Look at 'em.
جراحت بخاطر عقايد مسيحي ناه کنين
These guys are stumblin' through the alley. %%  Too-ra-loo-ra-loo-la% %
اين دو تا تو کوه ول ميشتناين
This guy takes a blunt object, fuckin'... Waah!
يکي يه شيء ضخيم ورميداره بامب
Hits the guy with the bandages around his head, right? Why? 'Cause he's smart.
ياروي بانديي شده رو ميزنه  ها؟ را؟    ون باهوش بوده
He knows the guy with the bandage around his ass, he ain't goin'nowhere.
ميدونسته يارو با بانداي دور کونش به هي جا نميرسه
He's goin'fuckin'nowhere!
اون بهي دردي نميخوره
Where are you goin'? Nowhere! That's right.
کجا ميري؟   هي جا  درسته
He ain't done yet. He comes over and jumps on this guy's back...
هنوز هيي نشده اون مياد و ميره
and crushes him to death.
رو شت اين يکي و اونو له ميکنه
I feel something big here.
احساس ميکنم يز بزري اينجا هست
I wouldn't be surprised to see a lot of these turnin' up.
من از ديدن اين جريانات تعجب ميکنم
[Smecker] Brilliant!
عاليه
So now we got a huge guy theory...
س ما يه نظريه براي هيکله داريم
and a serial crusher theory.
و يه نظريه قتل زنجيره اي
Top notch.
کامل
- What's your name? - Detective Greenly.
اسمت يه؟ کارااه رينلي
- Who the fuck are you? - That's who the fuck I am.
کدوم آشغالي هستي؟ آشغال منم
Listen, I gotta do this by the numbers.
وش کن  ميخوام سلسله مراتب رعايت بشه
I.D. Just came back on these guys.
اطلاعات فقط مربوط به ايناست اونا با اوباش
They got connections with the Russian mob.
روسي تماس داشتن اين يه مساله امنيتيه
That makes it a federal matter.
و سروان اسمکر براي هدايت تحقيق
And Agent Smecker here is heading up the investigation with our full cooperation.
با همکاري کامل ما هستن
- Why don't you get me a cup of coffee? - Who the hell is this?
را يه فنجون قهوه نميدين؟ مرتيکه کيه؟
- A cafe latte, twist of lemon, - What the fuck...
يه نسکافه   دوتا ليمو ه مري
- Chief, what the fuck is this? - Sweet 'N Low.
رئيس  اين جورشه؟ يالا جير
- Mitchell, Langley! - %%  [Stops]
ميشل  لنلي
- Yes, sir. - Find the manager of this building.
بله  قربان مدير اين ساختمونو يدا کن
See if he's had any complaints of water coming down...
ببين شکايتي از نشتي آب تو
in any of the apartments starting just this morning.
آارتمانا امروز صبح داشته
Langley, you take that building. Same thing.
لنلي اون يکي با تو کار برابر
Chaffey! Newman!
في   نيومن
- Yes, sir. - Look in the trash around their hands.
بله قربان    زباله اطرافشونو ناه کن
See if you can find me two bullet casings,
ببين ميتوني دو تا وکه يدا کني
fifty-caliber if my eyes serve me right.
کاليبر نجاه اه شام درست کار کنه
Newman, rip through this shit.
نيومن  اين کثافتو بشکاف
If this was a sink,
اه ظرفشويي وجود داشت
find me some metal parts.
برام ند قطعه فلزي يدا کن
Give me a drain cover, faucet or something.
دروش تخليه شيرآب يا غيره رو برام بيار
Got it right here. It's a 50-cal.
.درست اينجا   کاليبر 50
Chief, can you get ballistics down here...
رئيس مسير شليکو درآرين
and tell 'em they have to dig a 50-caliber slug...
و بين رو
out of a brick wall and locate another that's been fired through a Dumpster?
کاليبر 50 کار کنن
We have the best ballistics guy in the world.
از ديوار و از تو فاضلاب
- I can have him here in ten minutes. - How did you know that?
ما بهتريناشونو تو دنيا داريم فقط 10 دقيقه   - طور فهميدي؟
Liquid paraffin.
ارافين مايع
Came up positive.
جوابش مثبته
And bullet holes are usually a big clue.
و رد لوله بهترين سرنخه
Nobody reported any gunshots.
هيکس تيراندازي رو زارش نکرده
This is an Irish neighborhood. I'm surprised you even got a phone call.
اينجا يه محله ايرلنديه.  بازم خوبه يه تلفن شده
You know, I can't find the second one, sir.
دوميشون رو يدا نکردم قربان
Look under the body.
زير جسدو ناه کن
Oh, yeah, there it is.
اوه اينجاست
You guys ready for this?
شماها براش آماده اين؟
This was no gangland assassination.
اين يه قتل تبهکاري نبوده
Though creative, it was way too sloppy.
خيلي خلاقانه  خيلي شلخته
Something went wrong here. This has "personal" written all over it.
يه مشکلي اينجا هست همه جاش نوشته  "خصوصي"ـ
Agent Smecker. Yeah, this is all illegal loft housing.
سروان  اينا همش خونه هاي بدون مجوز
There's no manager on the premises, but they found a lady on the fourth floor...
و مدرن ولي يه خانوم طبقه هارمه
who said she had water dripping down on her whole place.
که فته همه جا آب که ميکرده
- It started just this morning. - Fourth floor, huh?
اول صبح بوده طبقه 4  ها؟
Mm-hmm.
هيم
Then we're headin' to the fifth.
س ما به نجمي هدايت ميشيم
Come on. Let's get out of here. You're reachin', man.
بريم بيرون  داري ميرسي مرد
- It's a theory. - I don't know. No way.
يه نظريه ست  نميدونم  راهي نيست
You know how big a guy's gotta be to do that? Fuckin' huge.
ميدوني ه هيکلي ميخواد؟ هيکل لعنتي
Oh, really? I might just be wantin' a bagel with my coffee.
اوه  واقعا؟ ممکنه يه کيک با قهوم بخوام
I ain't gettin' him no fuckin' bagel.
هي کيک لعنتي واسش نميارم
We'll start the ass kissing with you.
ماهم با تو شروع به موس موس ميکنيم
Agent Smecker. Agent...
سروان اسمکر
Listen, I know this neighborhood pretty good.
اين حوالي جاي خوبيه
There's a bar down the block named McGinty's.
يه ميکده باسم مکينتي
- It stands a good chance they were there last night. - Good work, Mitchell.
هست واسه آخرشب عاليه خوبه  ميشل
I'll check it out myself.
من خودم بررسيش ميکنم
[Connor] Look at the ceiling. Sense your touch alone.
سقفو ناه. فقط حس لامسه
Wait until you feel me move. Ooh.
تا وقت حرکت وايسا.
So quick you couldn't even feel it go, could you?
سريع نيستي ها؟
Let's try it again. Try it again. Look at the ceiling.
سعي دوباره  سقفو ناه
It's Doc.
دکتره
- Thanks for comin', Doc. - [Whispering] Jesus Christ!
تشکر دکتر   يا عيسي
What the fuck happened? Are-Are you b-b-boys all right?
ي شده؟   سالمين؟
- We're alive. - An F.B.I. Agent came by the bar...
زنده ايم.  يه مامور اف بي آي اومد ميکده
and he left me his c-c-ca...
ويزشو برام ذاشت
He left me his c-c... Oh, he fuckin' gave me this. Fuck!
يزشو داد بمن اون اينو بهم داد
- Ass! What are you gonna do? - [All Gasping]
لعنت الاغ   يکار ميکنين؟
We oughta turn ourselves in, tell him it was self-defense.
بايد خودمونو مرتب کنيم  بو دفاع شخصي بوده
Yeah, yeah, yeah. That's what he said.
آره   همونو فت
- How the fuck's he know that? We haven't spoken to anyone. - D-D-Don't know.
طور ميدونست؟ ما بهيکي نفتيم
He d-d-didn't say.
نميدونم نفت
All right. Listen, Doc, we need you to do us a favor.
وش کن دکتر يه لطفي بکن
- A-A-Anything. - Just hold on to this for us.
فقط اينو واسمون نهدار
- We're gonna come back for it when we get out. - Right.
وقتي دراومديم براش ميايم باشه
Fuck! Ass!
لعنت  الاغ
None of that cursing was directed at you. He's... He's a bit...
فحشا بتو نيست ...اون يخورده
First of all,
اولا
I'd like to thank whichever one of you...
ازتک تکتون متشکرم
doughnut-munching, barrel-assed,
نون جوا  الوندارا
pud-pulling sissies leaked this to the press.
آبجيايي که بمطبوعات درز دادن
That's just what we need now...
اينو فقط کم داشتيم  ندتا
some sensational story in the papers...
داستان احساسي تو روزنامه
making these boys out to be superheroes triumphing over evil.
که ازشون قهرمان ضد شيطان بسازه
Let me squash the rumors now.
شايعاتو خفه کنيد
These two are not heroes.
اين دوتا قهرمان نيستن
They're just two ordinary men...
اونا دوتا مرد معمولين که تو يه
who were put in an extraordinary situation,
موقعيت غيرعادي قرار رفتن
and they just happened to come out on top.
واتفاقي رو اومدن
Yes, nothing from our far-reaching computer system...
هيي تو کاميوتراي دقيقمون
has turned up diddly on these two.
دربارشون بدست نيومده
All we know is what we found out from the neighbors.
هر ي ميدونيم از همسايه هامونه
And the general consensus is,
و وفاق عمومي اينه که
they're angels.
اونا فرشته ان
But angels don't kill.
ولي فرشته ها نميکشن
And we got two bodies in the morgue...
وما دوتا مرده تو سردخونه داريم
that look like they've been serial-crushed...
که مثل قتل زنجيره اي بنظر مياد
- [Mocking Greenly] By some huge, friggin' guy. - [Laughter]
توسط ندتا نده بک
Are we considering these guys armed and dangerous?
ما اينا رو مسلح و خطرناک کرديم؟
Well, not armed.
خوب  غير مسلح
If they had guns, they would've used them. But dangerous? Very.
اه تفن داشتن  استفاده نميکردن ولي خطرناکن؟   خيلي
Now, what makes you think they're dangerous?
حالا ي فکر ميکنين خطرناکن؟
- Maybe they're just protectin' each other. - [Chattering]
شايد ازهم محافظت ميکردن
Hey, look, l-l-I'm not sayin' one way or the other.
ناه کن   نميخوام يه يز ديه بم
Just be careful and go by the protocol on this.
فقط مراقب باشين و مقرراتي
It's grunt police work that's gonna bring this one in.
يکار ليسيه بزره اين يکي رو ميخواد وارد کنه
These guys are miles away by now.
اونا مايلها از ما دورترن
But if you wanna beat your head against the wall, then here's what you're lookin'for.
اه ميخواين سرتونو بکوبين بديوار اينجا جاشه
They're scared, like two little bunny rabbits.
ترسيدن  مثل دوتا خروش ترسو
Anything in a uniform or flashing blue lights is gonna spook 'em.
هر يونيفورم يا راغي ميترسونشون
Okay? So the only thing we can do is put a potato on a string...
س فقط ميتونيم يه سيب زميني ورداريم
and drag it through South Boston.
و اونارو بسمت بوستون بکشيم
- Thanks for comin' out. - [Laughter]
مرسي که اومدين
You'd probably have better luck with a beer.
تو با يه آبجو بهتري
You would.
حق با توئه
- Oh, fuck. - [Smecker] Hey, Greenly.
اوه واي هي رينلي
Onion bagel, cream cheese.
نان ياز  نير خامه اي
This conversation is going to be recorded.
فتو ضبط ميشه
Just answer to the best of your knowledge.
به بهترين نحو جواب بدين
Excuse me, sir. Please.
ببخشين  لطفا
[Murphy] Okay, we're ready.
خوب آماده ايم
You boys are not under oath here. Just answer the questions.
شما قسم نميخورين  فقط بسوالا جواب ميدين
I'm assuming...
من مان ميکنم
you knew these guys from before, huh?
شماها از قبل اونا رو ميشناختين؟
We met them last night.
ما شب آخر ديديمشون
They had some pretty interesting bandages.
اونا بانداژاي زيادي داشتن
Know anything about that?
يزي دربارش ميدونين؟
Listen, if you want to fight, you can see you're outnumbered here.
اه ميخواين بجنين ميبينين که کمترين
We're trying to be civil, so I suggest you take our offer.
ما سعي ميکنيم متمدن باشيم س بهتون يه يشنهاد دارم
I make the offers.
من يشنهاد ميدم
Hey, Boris.
هي  بوريس
What would you do...
يکار ميکني
if I told you...
اه بهت بم
- your pinko Commie mother sucks so much dick, - [Laughter]
مادر لبوي کمونيستت که عالي ساک ميزنه
Her face looks like an egg?
صورتش مثل تخم مرغه؟
- Fuck you! - What are you doin'?
لعنت بتو يکار ميکني؟
Stay away! He can take care of himself!
وايسا کنار   مواظب خودش هست
Freeze, you fuckin' Irish faggots!
يخ کنين  آشغالاي ايرلندي
[Yells] Get the fuck up!
با بري
- Come on! - Get your fuckin' hands off of me!
يالا  دستاي کثافتتو ازم دور کن
Cuff yourself around the back! Cuff yourself!
از شتش دستبند بزن دستبند بزن
Cuff it!
ببندش
You know why I fucking come here?
ميدوني را
I come here to kill you.
اومدم بکشمت
But now, I no think I fucking kill you.
ولي الان نميخوام بکشمت
I kill your brother.
برادرتو ميکشم
Shoot him in the head.
بسرش ميزنم
- Fuck you! - Gotta go.
لعنت بتو   مشو
Connor!
کانر
It was just a fuckin' bar fight! You guys are fuckin' pussies!
اون فقط يه جن الکي بود شما کسکشاي لعنتي هستين
I hope your conscience is clear, Irishman.
اميدوارم وجدانت راحت باشه ايرلندي
So, how is it...
س طوره
- that you guys are fluent in Russian? - We paid attention in school.
که براتون روسي روونه تو مدرسه يادرفتيم
Do you speak any other languages?
زبوناي ديه ي؟
- Aye. Our mother insisted on it. - French?
هي مادرمون اصرار داشت فرانسوي؟
Oh, that's beautiful.
عاليه
- What's that? - It's Italian.
اون يه؟ ايتاليايه
- Jawohl. - [Spanish]
بله
What are you guys doin' workin' at a friggin' meat packing plant?
مال اين حوالي نيست مرد يه ايرلنديه خالصه
- Uh, Agent Smecker? The press is everywhere. - Yeah.
سروان اسمکر؟روزنامه ها
They're just goin' nuts for these guys. I don't know what you wanna do.
شيفته اينان  نميدونم ي ميين؟
You're not being charged. It's up to you. You wanna talk to 'em?
شما مجبور نيستين  با خودتونه ميخواين صحبت کنين؟
- Absolutely not. - No pictures either.
نه  هي عکسيم نه
Is there any way that we could stay here?
راهي هست اينجا بمونيم؟
Uh, yeah. You know, we have an extra holding cell you guys can...
بله يه سلول اضافي هست  ميتونين
- Can they stay? - [Smecker] Well, we'll have to check with your mom.
ميتونن بمونن؟ بايد با مامانتون هماهن کنيم
But it's okay with me if your friends sleep over.
من موافقم اه دوستاتم باشن
Time to feed the dogs.
وقت غذاي ساست
Okay, people. Okay.
خوب   همي
This is our official statement.
اين بيانيه رسمي ماست
The MacManus brothers are not being charged with a crime.
برادران مکمانوس متهم بجنايت نيستن
This is a clear-cut case of self-defense.
رونده اي واضح از دفاع شخصي
They are being released at an undisclosed time and location...
اونا در زمان و مکاني اعلام نشده آزادن
in accordance with their wishes.
مطابق خواستشون
- Do the MacManus brothers have any priors? - Can we speak to the brothers?
اونا سابقه دارن؟ ميتونيم صحبت کنيم؟
- [Man] Hey, Rocco, how you doin'? - Hey!
هي روکو طوري؟ هي
Yeah!
ها
What have you got there?
اونا رو طور يدا کردي؟
- Ahh. - Very nice.
اوه خيلي خوبه
[Monsignor] This poor soul...
اين روح بينوا
cried out for help.
التماس کمک ميکرد
They watched as he simply walked away.
اونا وقتي براحتي قدم ميزد ناه ميکردن
[Voice Overlapping] Indifference of good men!
بيتفاوتي به مردان خوب
Nobody wanted to get involved.
هيکس نميخواد سرش بياد
Nobody... [Echoing]
هيکس
- [Man's Voice] Whosoever shed my blood, - [Panting]
همه بايد خون مردي را بريزند که
By man shall his blood be shed.
بايد خونش ريخته شود
For in the image of God may deem a man.
همان مردي که خداوند مفروض داشته
Destroy all that which is evil.
تمام شيطانها را نابود  کن
So that which is good may flourish.
ون خوبي ممکنه رشد کنه
What the fuck is that?
اين ه کوفتيه؟
It's that fuckin' Russian's pager.
يجر اون روسي لعنتيه
Let's go.
بريم
How are ya?
طورين؟
- Keep the faith, man. - Fuckin' blow me.
مومن باش مرد لعنتي ترکوندم
- What was that? Have you got a pen? - Yeah. Here you go.
طور بود؟  يه خودکار داري؟ آره بفرماين
- Thanks. Be right back. - Good morning, son. How are ya?
مرسي صبح بخير  طورين؟
- Good morning. - We'd be honored if you would join us.
صبح بخير خوشحاليم اه با ما باشين
- See this? - What's this?
ميبيني؟  يه؟
Saints?
مقدسان؟
Body of Christ.
جسم مسيح
Amen.
آمين
That's not funny, man. Give it here, package boy.
شوخي نيست مرد  بدش ادو
Joey Beevo said it was important. Said to give it to him myself.
جويه بيوو فت مهمه فت بخودش بدم
Give me the fuckin' thing.
لعنتي رو بده
Sit the fuck down.
بتمر
So, I'm Rocco. I'm the funny man.
س من روکويم دلقک
I'm so fuckin' funny.
خيليم مضحکم
- [Whispers] Fuck you, Vincenzo. - Uh-huh.
تف بذاتت ويننزو اوه
How did you get that shiner on your eye?
کبودي رو شمت يه؟
What's the matter, someone didn't think you were very funny?
ي شده  بنظرکسي خيلي مضحکه نبودي؟
I caught your show at the Velvet Room at the Holiday Inn.
نمايشت تو اتاق والوت تو هتل هاليدي رو رفتم
Loved it when you busted into "Viva Las Vegas."
وقتي ترکوندي "درود لاس واس" خوشت اومد
- Hey, hey, hey. - [Shouting In Italian]
هي هي
You insignificant little fuck!
تو کثافت بياره
I always get my money, you cocksucking bastardo!
هميشه ولمو مييرم  حرومزاده خايه مال
The '90s are killing me.
ـ90ها ميکشنم
I shouldn't have done that.
انجامش نداده
You're not supposed to tell a guy you're gonna kill him no more.
نفتي ديه نميخواي بکشيش
I gotta tiptoe through the tulips with these assholes.
من از رو لها با اين کونيا نوکا ميرم
Taking all the fun out of the job.
همه هيجانشو مييرن
Pappa Joe, you want me to go now?
در جو ميخواين برم؟
All the boys tell me how you make them laugh when you come around.
بهم فتن جوري کله ملق ميزني؟
What a crackup you are. What do they call you?
ه جونوري هستي بهت ي مين؟
Uh, the... [Clears Throat]
اهم
The-The funny man.
دلقک
I'm having a shitty day. I'm depressed.
روز هي داشتم  داغونم
Tell me a funny joke.
يه جک باحال بو
Now?
الان؟
A joke? Uh...
يه جک؟ ها
Um, uh, a joke. Yeah, all right.
اه  يه جک     آره
Um, there's these, uh, three guys...
ايم سه تا مرد بودن
a-a-a spic,
يه زرد
a-a-a white guy and a black guy.
يه سفيد يه سياه
- Nigger! - Yeah.
کاکاسياه   آره
N-N... Yeah. And they're walkin' along the beach.
کنار ساحل قدم ميزدن
They see this pot. They rub it, a genie comes out.
يه راغ ميبينن  ميدزدنش يه غول ازش بيرون مياد
Genie says you can wish for anything you want. He asks the Mexican what he wants.
غول ميه آرزو کنين از مکزيکي ميرسه
And he goes,
اون ميه
"I want all my people in America to be happy and free in Mexico."
ميخوام همه مردمم تو آمريکا تو مکزيک شاد و آزاد باشن
So the genie... Poof! And all the spics are in Mexico.
غول فوت ميکنه همشون ميان تو مکزيک
- And then he asks the black guy... - Nigger.
بعد از سياهه ميرسه کاکاسياه
Yeah, that's what I said.
آره همون
He goes to the nigger, says, "What do you want?"
به کاکاسياه ميه تو ي ميخواي؟
And he goes,
اون ميه
"I want all my African...
ميخوام همه آفريقاييا
"my nigger brothers in America...
کاکاسياهاي برادرم تو آمريکا
to be back in Africa and happy and everything."
برردن آفريقا و شاد باشن
So the genie goes poof!
غول فوت ميکنه
And, um, all the niggers in America...
همشون تو آمريکا
are in Africa.
ميرن آفريقا
And this is goin'... I'm not funny today.
و همينطور  امروز خنده دار نيستم
I know. I'm havin' a hard day. L-l... This joke sucks.
ميدونم روز سختي داشتم جکه نميرخه
[Stammering] It's just a stupid joke.
يه جوک مزخرفه
Continue the joke.
ادامه بده
So the genie says to the white guy,
بعد غول به سفيده ميه
"What's your one wish?"
آرزوت يه؟
And the white guy goes, "You mean to tell me...
اون ميه يعني الان
all the niggers and spics are out of America?"
همه مکزيکيا و سياها خارج آمريکان؟
The genie goes, "Yeah." He says,
غول ميه آره     اون ميه
"Well, um, I'll have a Coke then."
من يه کوکا کولا ميخوام
"I'll have a Coke."
من کوکا کولا ميخوام
Yeah. Everybody's out,
همه ميريزن بيرون
so he just wants a Coke, 'cause that's all he needs.
ونکه فقط کوکا کولا ميخواست
- Tell me one more. - What?
يکي ديه    ي؟
Knock yourselves out.
خودتونو ناکار کنين
Fuckin' hell.
لامذهب
- Do you know what we need, man? Some rope. - Absolutely.
ميدوني ي ميخوايم؟ کمي طناب حتما
- What are ya, insane? - No, it ain't.
ته ديوونه؟ هيي
Charlie Bronson's always got rope.
ارلي برونسون هميشه طناب داشت
- What? - Yeah.
ي؟ آره
He's got a lot of rope strapped around him in the movies, and they always end up using it.
اون تو فيلما طنابا رو دورش ميييد و هميشه اونطوري تموم ميشدن
- You've lost it, haven't it? - No, I'm serious.
اشتباه ميکني  ها؟ نه جدا
That's stupid. Name one thing you'd need a rope for.
ديوونست  ييزي رو طناب فرض کن
You don't fuckin' know what you're gonna need it for. They just always need it.
حاليت نيست واسه ي بهش نياز داري اونا هميشه دارنش
What's this "they" shit? This isn't a movie.
اين اوناي لعنتي يه؟ يه فيلم نيست
Oh. Right.
اوه خودشه
Is that right, Rambo?
خود رامبويه؟
All right. Get your stupid fuckin' rope.
خوب   طناب لعنتيتو بير
I'll get my stupid rope.
من طناب رو دارم
I'll get it.
دارمش
There's rope right there.
دقيقا اونجا
You nervous?
عصبي اي؟
- A bit. - Myself as well.
يه خورده منم
Hello?
الو؟
Uh-huh. Room number?
شماره اتاق؟
Have we got a time of death?
زمان مرو داريم؟
- We got a body count? - [Gasps]
شمارش افرادو داريم؟
- [Whimpers] - Uh-huh. I'll be down there in a bit.
فورا اونجام
Keep the press out.
بمطبوعات اجازه ندين
- What are you doin'? - I just wanted to cuddle.
يکار ميکني؟ ميخوام نوازش کنم
Cuddle? What a fag.
نوازش؟ يه حمال
Ooh.
اوه
This is a fucking slaughterhouse.
يه سلاخي کامله
- How many bodies, Greenly? - Eight.
ندتا رينلي؟
Aw, shit. I forgot about that one. Nine. Nine?
فراموشش کردم ـ9   9؟
While Greenly's out gettin' coffee, anybody else want anything?
رينلي قهوه درست کنه هيي کسي ميخواد؟
Shit!
اه
[Smecker] So, Duffy,
س دافي
you got any theories to go with that tie?
در رابطه با اون کراوات نظري داري؟
Look, fuck all these other guys.
همه رو با دادن
This was their target... the fag man.
اينه هدفشون    حمال
The what man?
ي؟
The fat man.
اق
Well, Freud was right.
خوب حق با فرويد بود
So you think they came for the fag man, huh?
س بنظرتون اونا براي حماله اومدن؟
What do you base this upon?
اساسش يه؟
He was the only one done right. Double tap back of the head.
فقط اون درسته  2تا ضربه شت سر
- [Smecker] And the pennies? - New hit man wants to leave his mark.
وسکه ها؟   تيرانداز ميخواد اثرشو بذاره
That's a possibility.
ممکنه
Now you Irish cops are perkin'up.
ليساي ايرلندي که مغرورين
That's two sound theories in one day,
ـ2تا تئوري اصلي تو 1 روز
neither of which deal with abnormally-sized men.
هيکدوم با مرداي نافرم جور نيست
Kind of makes me feel like Riverdancing.
کمي بمن حس رقص ميده
Another possibility is they were placed there with religious intent.
نيت مذهبي هم امکانش هست
Okay, some cultures still put pennies in the eyes of the dead. Or silver.
بعضي فرهنا هنوز تو شم مرده سکه ميذارن
The Italians, the Greeks.
ايتاليايي ها   يوناني ها
[Duffy] Sicilians.
سيسيلي ها
So, what's the "symbology" there?
س نمادشناسي ميخواد؟
The "symbology"?
نمادشناسي؟
Now that Duffy has relinquished his King Bonehead crown,
دافي که از تاج ادشاهيش شم وشيد
I see we have an heir to the thrown.
اثر ميراث اونو ميبينم
I'm sure the word you were looking for was "symbolism." What is the symbolism there.
کلمه اي که دنبالش بودي سمبوليسمه ه سمبوليسمي اينجاست
Let me explain it to you.
بذار توضيح بدم
In Greek and Roman mythology,
در اسطوره شناسي رومي و يوناني
when you died, you'd have to pay the toll to Charon,
وقتي که مردين بايد به حاکم باج بدين
the boatman who ferried you across to the Gates of Judgment.
قايقراني که شما رو از دروازه داوري عبور ميده
This made sure the dead came to atone for what they did during their lives,
اينجوري مرده براي اعمالش کفاره داده
Detective Alapopskalius.
کارااه آلاوسکاليوس
Jesus. You're the first one that ever got that.
خدايا  تو اوليني هستي که درکش کردي
Yeah, well, I'm an expert in nameology.
خوب من در نام شناسي متخصصم
These burns indicate that they used silencers.
اينا نشون ميده اونا صدا خفه کن داشتن
Look at these entry and exit wounds.
به زخماي داخلي و خارجي ناه کن
They're almost identical.
اونا تقريبا يکين
The two bullets went in here through the top of the skull,
وله ها از بالاي جمجمه رفتن
crisscrossed, and exited through the eyeballs.
مورب و از کاسه شم خارج شدن
This one clue tells us three distinct facts.
اين سرنخ 3 تا حقيقتو بما ميه
- Number one. Duffy? - They shot him at a downward angle.
يک  دافي؟    اونا رو به ايين شليک کردن
- They put him on his knees? - Excellent. Number two. Greenly.
رو زانواش ذاشتنش عاليه   دو   رينلي؟
They shot him at a downward angle?
اونا رو به ايين شليک کردن؟
It tells us he was the last to die.
ميفهميم که اون آخرين مر بوده
And number three. Dolly.
و 3    دالي
There was two shooters.
ـ2 تا تيرانداز بودن
- Fan-freakin'-tastic. - Hey, wait a minute.
خارق العاده هي يه لحظه
Stay with me, boys. What did they do...
صبر کنين  اونا يکار کردن
to make two such identical wounds?
تا 2 تا زخم يکسان بسازن
Two men of similar height dropped this guy down.
دو مرد هم قد اونو انجام دادن
Each puts some iron to his head and boom! That's all she frickin' wrote.
!لوله رو ميذارن رو سرش و بن تمامش نوشته هاي اون زنه
- What about one guy, two guns? - Ah, possible.
يه مرد با 2 تا تفن ي؟ اوه  ممکنه
But unlikely. The angles are too extreme.
ولي کمتر   زاويه ها خيلي دورن
A guy holding two guns to the back of your noodle is going to shoot straight ahead.
مردي که 2 تا تفنو شت مختون مييره مستقيم شليک ميکنه
He wouldn't cock out his elbows. It makes no sense.
اون آرنجاشو کج نميکنه    احتمالش کمه
Besides, are you telling me one guy came in here...
ميين يه نفر مياد اينجا
and killed eight men with eight extremely well-aimed shots in just a few seconds?
و 8 مرد کاملا مسلحو در ند ثانيه ميکشه؟
No way. It had to be at least two.
نه   اونا حداقل 2 نفرن
[Scoffs] You and your fuckin' rope.
تو و اون طناب لعنتيت
- I told you there would be a shaft. - Just like on television.
فتم اونجا يه کاناله  درست مثل تلويزيون
Fuck.
تف
Where the fuck are you goin'?
کدوم قبري ميري؟
Shh! I fuckin' hear some shit out here.
شش   يه صداهايي ميشنوم
Fuck you. I'm sweatin' my ass off draggin' your fuckin' rope around.
کونم از دست اين طنابت اره شد
- It must weigh 30 pounds. - Shh!
وزنش 30 ونده شش
We are doin' some serious shit here. Now, get a fuckin' hold of yourself!
داريم ند ميزنيم محکم خودتو نهدار
Oh, fuck you! I'm not the rope-totin' Charlie Bronson wannabe...
من طناب جمع کن جناب ارلي برونسون نيستم
- that's gettin' us fuckin' lost. - Would you fuckin' shut it!
برامون درددسرسازه ميتوني ببنديش
You mother...
مادربخطا
- Jesus fuckin' Christ. - Oh, shit!
عيسي مسيح اوه تف
[Together] Shepherds we shall be for Thee, my Lord, for Thee.
اي شبان ما از آن توييم  سرورم از آن تو
Power hath descended forth from Thy hand.
اکنون قدرت در دستان توست
Our feet may swiftly carry out Thy command.
اهايمان بسرعت فرمانت را اجرا ميکند
So we shall flow a river forth to Thee, and teeming with souls shall it ever be.
ما در رودخانه ات جريان داريم و از ارواح آن باروريم
[Man's Voice] And I shall count thee among my favored sheep.
و من بايد تو را رمه خود بدانم
And you shall have the protection of all the angels in heaven.
و تو محافظ تمام فرشتان در بهشتي
Television.
تلويزيون
Television is the explanation for this.
توضيحش تلويزيونه
You see this in bad television.
تو برنامه هاي خشن ديدينش
The little assault guys creepin' through the vents, comin' in through the ceiling.
مهاجما از تو هواکش سقف داخل ميشن
That James Bond shit never happens in real life. Professionals don't do that.
جيمز باند واقعيت نداره حرفه ايا اينجوري نيستن
Well, name one thing you're gonna need this stupid fuckin' rope for.
اسم اين طناب بازي رو ي ميي
- That was way easier than I thought. - Aye.
يه راه آسونتر براش بود
On TV, you've always got that guy that jumps over the sofa.
تو تلويزيون اون از رو مبل ميريد
- And then you've gotta shoot him for ten fuckin' minutes too. - Aye.
و بعد 10 دقيقه تيراندازي ميکرد
- We're good. - Yes, we are.
عالي بود   آره بوديم
Now, what do you think is in that little case there?
نظرت راجع به کيف يه؟
- Fuck me! - Oh.
با منو
The hits just keep on comin'.
وله ها آيندمونو حفظ کردن
Ow! Give it a smell.
بوش کن
- I love our new job. - [Doorbell Buzzing]
شغل جديدمونو دوست دارم
Bastard. This has got to be his big break.
حرومزاده  اين واسه استراحتش بوده
- Yeah. - We've got to fuck with him, right?
بايد سربسرش بذاريم
- Okay. - [Laughing]
باشه
Shh.
شش
Open the door. I'm gonna grab him by the fuckin' hair.
درو وا کن  ميخوام موهاي لعنتيشو ن بزنم
- [Screaming] - Sit down!
بشين
- Get down! Shut up! - Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
بشين  خفه   شليک نکنين
- We're on the same side. Please, don't shoot. - Get on the ground!
ما از هميم  شليک نکنين بشين رو زمين
Don't shoot, don't shoot. We're on the same side.
شليک نکنين  ما از هميم
Boss must've sent me in as backup. I'm Rocco!
رئيس منو کمکي فرستاده  منم روکو
- I'm the funny man. That ain't my name. - Where's your gun?
دلقکم  اون اسمم نيست  کو تفنت؟
- I'm the fuckin' funny man! It's right here. Right here.
تفنت کو؟  من دلقک لعنتيم  همينجاست
That ain't my real name.
اسم واقعيم اون نيست
What the fuck? Jeez!
ه مزخرفيه؟  واي
It's a fuckin' six-shooter!
اون يکي از 6 تيراندازه
- [Panting] - There's nine bodies, genius!
در اصلش 9 تا
What the fuck were you gonna do, laugh the last three to death, funny man?
ه غلطي ميکردي  خنده آخرتو بکن دلقک؟
Pappa Joe said there was only two! In and out!
اا جو فت درون و بيرون فقط 2 تان
Boy, you guys sure did a good job.
شماها کارتون خيلي درسته
Ah, shit. You guys are good, huh?
شما ها خوبين  ها؟
Cool masks. Where'd you get 'em?
ماسکاي با حال  از کجا آوردينشون؟
- We gotta do him right here! - Right now!
همينجا  همين الان
- Don't, please! I'm the funny man! - Right.
نه خواهشا   من دلقکم   ها
- Don't kill me! Don't kill me, please! - Right!
منو نکشين  خواهشا  خوب
I'm the funny man!
من دلقکم
[Connor] What a fuckin'idiot!
عجب ابلهي
Fuckin'... What the fuckin' fuck... Who the fuck...
واو ه نديه  کدوم ندي
Fuck this fuckin'... How did you two fuckin'fucks... Fuck!
لعنت بهش  شماها يکار کردين؟
Well, that certainly illustrates the diversity of the word.
مثال خوبي براي تنوع دنياست
All these guys are Russian mob.
همشون تبهکار روسين
But not like those two peons in the alley the other day.
نه مثل اون ادواي اونروز تو کوه
These guys are all syndicate bosses and underbosses.
همشون رئيس و معاوناي روهن
I have a dossier on every man in this room.
واسه هر کدومشون يه رونده دارم
Since the Iron Curtain has gone down,
وقتي آيرون کورتين افول کرد
the Russian syndicates have started to come here.
تبهکاراي روسي باينجا اومدن
And in the spirit of Glasnost, the Soviets have opened their borders to the Mafia.
و در لواي آزادي بيان    شوروي مرزاشو براي مافيا باز کرد
But the Italians, they aren't convinced...
ولي ايتاليايي ها قانع نشدن
the grounds in Mother Russia are fertile enough for organized crime yet.
زمينهاي روسيه مادري هنوز براي جنايات سازمان يافته حاصلخيزن
So they ain't ready to commit. But the Russians are coming here anyway.
س اونا حاضر به اطاعت نبودن ولي روسا هرجورشده ميان اينجا
They are unwelcome.
اونا ناخوانده ان
So, what we have here, gentlemen,
س اينجا  آقايون
is possibly the beginning...
امکان شروع
of the first international mob war.
اولين جن جنايي بين الملليه
Unless I've totally missed something.
مه من کاملا خطا کنم
I'm live from the Copley Plaza Hotel,
زراش زنده از هتل کلي لازا
where we have just been informed that the largest multiple murder...
مطلع شديم بزرترين قتل روهي
in Boston's history has just taken place.
در تاريخ بوستون اينجا رخ داده
We have learned that there were nine victims,
باخبريم که کشته ها 9 نفرن
all deeply involved in a notoriously violent Russian crime syndicate,
همي عضو يک سازمان کاملا جنايي روسي
right here in Boston.
اينجا در بوستون
Anybody you think is evil?
هرکسي بنظر شروره؟
Aye.
آره
Don't you think that's a little weird, a little psycho?
يه خو.رده عجيب و رواني نيست؟
Do you know what I think is psycho, Roc?
روکو ميدوني ي روانيه؟
It's decent men with loving families.
مرداي شايسته با خونواده هاي مهربون
They go home every day after work, and they turn on the news.
هر روز بعد از کار ميرن خونه و اخبارو روشن ميکنن
You know what they see? They see rapists...
ميدوني ي ميشه؟ اونا زنا کارا رو ميبينن
and murderers and child molesters.
و قاتلا و کودک آزارا
They're all gettin' out of prison.
همشون آزادن
Mafiosos...
جنايتکاري رو
gettin' caught with 20 kilos...
با 20 کيلو مييرن
gettin' out on bail the same fuckin' day.
از حبس همونروز بيرون مياد
And everywhere, everyone thinks the same thing...
و همه جا همه ميدونن
that someone should just go kill those motherfuckers.
که يکي بايد اون مادرجنده ها رو بکشه
Kill 'em all. Admit it.
همشونو بشکه  قبول کن
Even you've thought about it.
دربارش فکر کردي
You guys should be in every major city.
شماها بايد تو هر شهر بزري باشين
This is some heavy shit.
اين ندکاري سنينيه
This is like "Lone Ranger" heavy, man.
مثل "مبارز تنها "سنينه  مرد
Fuck it! There's so much shit that pisses me off!
تف با ندکارياتون شاشيدين بمن
You guys should recruit, 'cause I'm sick and fuckin' tired...
نيروي تازه ميخواين   ون من مريض و خستم
of walkin' down the street waitin' for one of these crack-pipin',
از خيابونردي و انتظار واسه اين آشغالاي
ass-wipin', motherless lowlifes to get me!
کون اک کن بي مادر بيوجود تا منو بيرن
Hallelujah, Jaffar.
درود  جعفر
So you're not just talkin' about mob guys, right?
س فقط اوباشو نميين  ها؟
You're talkin' about pimps and drug dealers and all that shit, right?
شما جاکشا و موادفروشا و همه لعنتيا رو ميين  ها؟
Oh, yeah.
اوه  آره
Fuck. You guys could do this every goddamn day.
لعنت  شما هر روزي ميتونستين انجامش بدين
We're sort of like 7-Eleven.
ما يجور 7-يازدهيم
We're not always doin' business, but we're always open.
هميشه کاسب نيستيم ولي هميشه بازيم
- Mmm. That is nicely put. - Thank you very much.
ممم  تعبير خوبيه خيلي ممنون
I will fuck you up, dude.
قيافه ها همتونو ميام
So then we go right through the fuckin' ceiling like this... [Continues, Indistinct]
از شت بومي مثل اين رد ميشيم
Oh, boy. You fuckin' guys. You ruined me.
اوه لامذهبا .  داغونم کردين
I'm fuckin' done.
من کردمش
Permanent fuckin' package boy.
سر اکتي ثابت لامسب
Who said that? You can take credit on that, you know?
کي فته؟ اون معتبره  ميدوني؟
What, are you serious?
ي  جدا؟
Yeah. Fuck it.
ها  لعنت بهش
If you think about it, it's all you can do, really.
اه بهش فکر ميکني واقعا همش همينه
I mean, you can't go in there and tell him it was us.
منظورم نميشه بهش بين ما بوديم
[Connor] Climb the corporate ladder, boy.
از نردبون سازمان برو بالا   سر
Don Rocco.
عاليجناب روکو
Fuck it.
تف
I'm doin' it. I deserve it.
انجامش ميدم  کار منه
I've been workin' for those fat bastards since I've been in high school.
از دبيرستانم واسه اون آشغالا کار کردم
Look at this fuckin' place. They're fuckin' me, man.
اينجا رو  ناه کنين اونا دهنمو سرويس کردن
They can suck my pathetic little dick!
اونا کيرمو ميليسن
And I'll dip my nuts in marinara sauce...
منم شلامو تو سس مارينا ميريزمو
just so the fat bastards can get a taste of home while they're at it.
اون کثافتام بعد عمري طعم خوني رو ميشن
Fuck it! I'm doin'it.
تف بهش   کار منه
It is done! Shit!
انجام شده     اه
- Shit! Shit! - Oh, my God!
اه  اه     اوه خدايا
- What the fuck! - I'm hit!
عجب ندي     من تير خوردم
Oh, fuck!
اوه   تف
[Rocco] What the fuck!
ه ندي
I can't believe that just fuckin' happened!
باورم نميشه همين افتضاحي شده
- Is it dead? - Oh, my God!
مرده؟    اوه خدايا
Donna's gonna be angry about her cat.
دونا واسه ربش ناراحت ميشه
Shit.
اه
She's on every drug known to man.
اون فوق هر دواييه واسه انسان
She'd have sold the thing for a dime bag. Screw her.
واسه يه ساک 10 سنتي يزو فروخته   باش
I do kind of feel like an asshole, though.
ولي حس يه کوني رو دارم
Yeah, Roc, you sound real remorseful there.
اوه روک  تو واقعا اونجا شيمون بودي
She ain't been around in weeks anyhow.
بازم اين هفته ها اطراف نبوده
Listen, something's been botherin' me about last night.
وش کن يه يز منو از اون شب آزار ميده
What?
ي؟
What if your boss knew how many fellows were supposed to be there?
رئيست طور ميدونست اونجا ند نفرن؟
- What are you... What are you sayin'? - Think about it.
ي ميي- ي ميي؟ فکر کن
Nine men, six bullets.
نه مرد  شش لوله
Think they sold me out? No way. No way.
مثلا اونا بهم خيانت ميکردن؟ ولش  ولش
Listen, he probably knew you'd end up nailin' the fat guy,
شايد ميدونسته تو کار هيکله رو تموم کردي
maybe one or two more, but he had to know you weren't walkin' out of there.
يکي يا دوتا بيشتر  ولي اون ميدونسته تو اونجا رو ترک نکردي
Figure it out. The shooter's dead at the scene.
حلش کن   تيرانداز تو صحنه ميميره
There's no in-depth investigation.
هي معماي ييده اي وجود نداره
They'll just slide right off his fuckin' back.
اونا درست بطرف نارو ميزنن
'Cause what the fuck?
ي باعثش شده؟
As much as I love you, man, you are not exactly Don Corleone.
خيلي دوستت دارم مرد  تو اصلا عاليجناب کارلئونه نيستي
No, no, that...
نه نه اون
That's just not the way things are done. Besides, how does he know...
اونجوري نبوده  تازه ـ طور اون ميدونسته
I just don't get in there, see there's too many of'em, serve 'em their fuckin' food...
ببين خيلي از اونا هستن براشون غذاي کوفتيشونو سرو ميکنن
Because he fuckin' knows you, Roc!
ون اون لعنتي ميشناستت روکو
A smooth hitter would have gone in there, seen it was a fuckin' wash and slipped out.
يه تيرانداز ساده اونجا ميره ـ ميشوره و ميلغزه
But you, he knows this is your only shot.
ولي اون ميدونست اين تنها تيرته
You've been waitin' 18 fuckin' years.
تو 18 سال تمام وايستادي
No. No, no. That-That...
نه نه     اون اون
That just ain't the way... No, that's bull... That's bullshit.
اونطوري نه   رنده
You don't know what you're talkin' about. That's just not the way things happen.
نميدوني ي ميي اونجوري نبوده
I mean, thanks for your concern and all, but that just ain't the thing of it.
ميم واسه نرانيت متشکرم ولي همش اون نيست
Do me a favor, all right? Just roll it around a bit on your way in.
يه لطفي کن باشه؟ اونو تو مسير بالا ايينش کن
- Will you for me? - No. No rollin'.
ازم ميخواي؟ نه نه بالا ايين
Nothin' needs to be rolled. Fuck!
بالا ايين نميخواد تف
- Where the fuck are you goin'? Did you tell him? - Of course I fuckin' told him.
کدوم وري ميري؟بهش فتي؟ البته که بهش فتم
- Then what the fuck? - You guys don't know that shit for sure!
س شه؟  نميدونين که  واسه محکم کاري
Oh, you're such a fuckin' retard!
خيلي ابلهي
- Hey, fuck you! - Oh, man, use your fuckin' brain for once!
تف بذاتت   يه دفعه مختو کار بنداز
Is it so unbelievable that they don't fuckin' care about ya?
خيلي عجيبه که اونا مراقبتن؟
Oh, yeah, you two fuckin' Micks know what's goin' on, huh?
شما داغوناي لعنتي ميدونين ي داره ميشه  ها؟
- Fuck you both! - This is not a fuckin' thing you should gamble on, all right?
تف بهردوتون  الان وقت قمار نيست مه نه؟
I'm the fuck out of here.
از اينجا ميرم
Fine! Fuck it!
خوبه  لعنت
What kind of flowers you want at your funeral, you dumb wop?
جور لي واسه دفنت ميخواي کسخل؟
- It's the last time I'm gonna see ya! - I'll be back at nine!
دفعه آخرمه .ساعت 9 برميردم
- Bury the fuckin' cat! - Listen, you get in there...
ربه رو خاکش کن   تو اومدي اونجا
and you start gettin' a bad vibe, you get the fuck out quick!
تو بدمستي کردي  زود برو بيرون
- [Ringing] - Hello?
سلام؟
- [Rocco] Murph. - Hey, Roc. You okay?
مورف   هي روک  خوبي؟
Anybody call for me?
هيکي کارم داشته؟
No, man. Are you sure you're okay?
نه . مطمئني خوبي؟
I'm fuckin' fine.
خوبم
I'll catch you on the flip side.
سمت کناره مييرمت
[Woman] Here, kitty, kitty, kitty.
کيتي کيتي کيتي
Pack your shit! Pack your shit! We gotta get out of here!
کولتو ببند   کولتو ببند بايد از اينجا بريم
- We gotta get out! - What the fuck are you talkin' about?
بايد بريم ي ميي؟
I killed them! Oh, Jesus, I killed them all!
کشتمشون همشونو کشتم
- Just calm down. Tell us what happened. - No!
آروم بيا ايين   بو ي شده   نه
- [Together] Rocco! - [Connor] Calm down, man.
روکو   آروم مرد
Fuck you! You start gettin' excited, motherfucker!
تف بذاتت داري شلوغ ميکني مادرجنده
- We gotta go! - [Woman] Rocco!
بايد بريم روکو
- Well, how many were there? - Fuckin' hurry the fuck up!
خوب   ندتا بودن؟ بيشرفا زود باشين؟
All right! I love this shit!
باشه   عاشق اين جورشم
- What the fuck is wrong with you, Roc? - The cocksucker sold me out!
ه مرته روکو؟  خايه مال منو فروخت
Didn't I tell you, Roc? Did they pull on you first?
نفتم  روک؟   دفعه اولشونه؟
What am I doin'? I'm in it at Lakeview!
يکار ميکنم؟ وسط درياه
Lakeview the deli, Roc?
درياه دلربا  روک؟
- Looks like we got us a new fuckin' recruit. - [Together] Rocco!
مثکه يه تازه کار داريم   روکو
- What? - Where's my cat?
يه؟    ربم کجاست؟
I killed your cat, you druggie bitch.
ربتو کشتم  جنده معتاد
- God. Why? - What?
خدايا را؟   ي؟
I felt it would bring closure to our relationship.
احساس ميکنم اون رابطمونه خاتمه ميده
- You killed my-my... - Your what?
تو  يزمو کشتي؟   يزتو؟
- My... - Your fuckin' what? Huh? Your what, bitch?
يز   يز؟ها؟يزتو  جنده؟
I'll shoot myself in the head...
خودمو ميکشم
if you can tell me that cat's name!
اه اسم ربه لعنتي رو ببري
Go ahead! Your what? Your precious little...
يالا  يزتو؟   کوولوي باارزشتو
- Skippy. Skippy. - Oh, Jesus. What color was it, bitch?
اسکيي اسکيي   اون ه رني بود جنده؟
Don't you fuckin' yell at her like that, you prick!
سرش داد نزن سوراخ
Shut your fat ass, Rayvie!
کون شادتو ببند   رايوي
I can't buy a pack of smokes without runnin' into nine guys you fucked!
يه اکت سيارم براي 9 تايي که اييدي نميخرم
- [Whimpering] - Damn! Son of a bitch.
لعنت  تخمس
[Connor] Let's go!
بريم
Let's get the fuck outta here!
ازاين آشغالي بريم بيرون
Those rat fucks! All of them were all laughin' at me, man.
اون موشاي آشغال  همشون بهم خنديدن مرد
- Are you sure you killed them, Roc? - Fuckin'-A right I did.
مطمئني کشتيشون؟   يکار درستم همونه
I had a goddamn turkey shoot over there.
يه بوقلمون بازي اونجا درآوردم
- Anybody call for me? - [Murphy] No, man. Are you sure you're okay?
هيکي کارم نداشت؟   نه مطمئني خوبي؟
I'm fuckin' fine.
خوبم
I'll catch you on the flip side.
سمت کناره مييرمت
I'll bet it was a fuckin' test.
شرط ميبندم آزمايش بود
Vincenzo came in here shootin' his mouth off. He made sure we knew.
ويننزو مياد تيرو تو دهنش ميزنه   اون مطمئنه ما ميدونيم
But we did what we were supposed to, huh?
ولي ما کارمونو انجام ميديم  هاه؟
We kept our mouths shut.
دهنمونو ميبنديم
You? You did your part.
تو؟  تو کارتو کردي
Fuck!
تف
They know we're goodfellas now.
ميدونن ما الان خوبيم
We'll get taken care of, baby.
ما مراقبت ميکنيم ـ عزيز
What? Did everyone know?
ي؟  همه ميدونن؟
Next thing you're gonna tell me Sal was in on it.
سال يه يز ديه راجع بهش فتي
Vincenzo told Sal first. That fat fuck knew before we did.
ويننزو اول به سال فت. اق بيشرف قبل ازما خبر داشت
At least we got our funny man back, huh?
لااقل ما به دلقکمون رسيديم
- That was funny, wasn't it? That was real fucking funny! - No, not me! Not me!
مسخرست نه؟  واقعا مسخرست نه  من. نه . من نه
Huh? Ha! Funny! Funny!
ها؟  مسخره؟  مسخره؟
- Funny! Funny! Funny! - [Gun Hammer Clicking]
مسخره  مسخره  مسخره
- Funny! - %%  Full, full% %
مسخره
- %%  Full%% - Listen, Roc, did anybody see ya?
روک هيکي ديدت؟
Fuck, man, I might as well have gone around postin' flyers.
اوه  مرد من بخوبيه رنده هاي ستي ريدم
Right out in public, man. [Whimpering]
درست وسط جمعيت
Liberating, isn't it?
آزادسازي  مه نه؟
- Let's fucking go! - You know, it is a bit.
بريم.  ميدوني يه خوردشه
[Rocco] Conner, stop the car! Stop the fucking car, man!
کانر ماشينو نهدار  لامسبو نش دار
Vincenzo, that fat motherfucker, Yakavetta's right hand!
ويننزو  اون مادرجنده اق دست راست ياکاوتا
He's the one who set me up, then he went around telling everybody I was as good as dead.
اون  منو راه انداخت ـ بعدش به همه به راحت مرد
Goes there every Wednesday night 10:00, jerks off on the same titty dancer. Never misses.
هر هارشنبه شب راس 10 اونجاست با اون رقاصک جلق ميزنه . خطا نميکنه
- Yeah, so? - So? So let's kill the motherfucker!
اه  س؟     س؟ بريم مادر جنده رو بکشيم
I mean, what are you guys? That's your new thing, right?
س هستين سرا؟   مورد جديدتونه   ها؟
- Yeah, well... - Ah, what the fuck!
آره خوب ـ  اوه ه وضعي
I mean, who makes the cut? Is there a raffle or something?
س کار کيه؟   اونجا قمار و اينجورياست؟
To tell you the truth, those first ones, they just sort of fell onto our laps.
فتن حقيقت بتو ـ اول اونا اونا فقط يجور ادو تو بغلمونن
Well, what do you do?
خوب ـ س ي؟
We haven't really got a system of decidin' who, Roc. It's...
ما يه سيستم براي تصميم يري که کي نداريم ـ روک اون
Me! Me! I'm the guy!
من  من  ـ منم
I know everyone, their habits, who they hang out with, who they talk to!
همه رو ميشناسم ـ عادتاشون با کي قرار دارن  با کي حرف ميزنن
I got phone numbers, addresses! I know who they're fuckin'!
شماره تلفنا آدرسا رو دارم. بيشرفا رو ميشناسم
I know where they live!
ميدونم کجا ساکنن
We could kill everyone.
همه رو ميکشيم
So what do you think?
خوب ي ميي؟
I'm strangely comfortable with it.
من عجيب براش راحتم
That's him.
همونه
- Okay, Roc. - [Laughing]
خوب  روک
[Whispering] What? You guys got masks.
يه؟ شماها ماسک دارين
You look like Mush Mouth from Fat Albert. [Laughing Continues]
تو مثله عروسکاي آلبرت اقه اي
Fine. Fuck it! When we're done, she can I.D. Me.
لعنتي  وقتي ميريم تو ميتونه منو بشناسه
I don't care. Just trying to be professional, but no!
مهم نيست سعي کنين حرفه اي باشين ـ ولي نه
- It looks fine. - No, fuck it.
خوبه . نه ـ تف بهش
No, shut the fuck up! You look good. Put it on. You look fucking scary, man.
نه خفه شو ـ خوبه ـ بوشش بد ترسناک شدي مرد
Now, Roc, are you sure that you're "O-B-kay-B"?
خوب روک مطمئني خ . خوبي . خ
[Clears Throat] She was in here when it all went down.
اون اينجا بود وقتي همه تموم ميکنن
- Can she I.D. 'em? - No.
ميتونه شناساييشون کنه؟   نه
- There were wearin' masks. - Of course they were.
ماسک وشيده بودن  ـ  البته اونا بودن
You scream, you're dead! Which one's he in?
داد بزني  مردي ـ تو کدومه؟
And don't make like you don't know who the fuck I'm talkin' about!
نو نميدوني درباره کدوم بيشرفي حرف ميزنم
- Don't you talk to me like that, you dirty little girl. - [Woman Moaning]
اونجوري حرف نزن دختره کثيف
Oh, yeah. Give it to Daddy.
اوه ـ بدش به بابا
Oh, this is one sick motherfucker.
اوه اين يه مادرجنده مريضه
- How many? - Three.
ند تا؟ ـ 3 تا
Two of them did the shootin'.
دوتا شون تير زدن
[Conner, Murphy] "...and teeming with souls shall it ever be."
و ر از روحيه لازم
Our little theory from last night just got shot to shit.
تئوري کويک شب ذشتمون مزخرف بود
Something new is going on here.
اين جريان جديديه
After talking to the dancer,
بعد از صحبت با رقاص
we know their mark was the guy in the middle booth.
ردشون مرديه که اطاقک وسطي بوده
After she watches 'em whack him, she passes out.
بعديکه ديده زدنش زن بيهوش شده
What the fuck are you doing?
ه غلطي ميکني؟
I'll tip her!
بهش انعام دادم
Why are there two extra victims?
را دوتا قرباني اضافه؟
- Witnesses. - No way they could have seen.
شاهدا ـ نميشده اونا نبينن
Allow me to enlighten you gentlemen...
بذارين آقايون آشناتون کنم
to the protocol of the porno industry,
با تشريفات صنعت سکس
as I'm sure you've never been in one of these places before.
مطمئنم شما تو اينجاها قبلا نبودين
A man goes into the booth, puts the money through the slot,
مردي که به اتاقک ميره ـ ولو تو ظرف ميذاره
the dancer gets it on the other side.
رقاص طرف ديه اونو مييره
She hits the button, the door goes up.
دکمه رو فشار ميده تا در بالا بره
Now there's only glass between you, and that's "little fireman" time.
حالا فقط يه شيشه بين شما و  مرد آتيشيه
No way they could have seen it.
اونا نميشده نبينن
Those doors were down, so that means this:
:اون درا ايين رفتن که يعني
They looked in, down through the peepholes,
اونا بداخل ناه کردن از ايين روزنه ها
saw these guys, opened the doors from the inside,
اينا رو ديدن که درا رو از داخل ايين دادن
pop, pop, pop, right through the glass.
تق تق تق از وسط شيشه ها
Why?
را؟
- It's like a scumbag yard sale. - We should come down here once a week and clean house.
مثل آشغالدوني ـ بايد هفته اي يبار بيايم اينجا و خونه رو تميز کنيم
Maybe the three guys had something in common.
شايد اين 3 نفر رابطه اي باهم داشتن
No, this guy's big-time. These two are street-walkin' scum.
نه اين يکي وقت اصلي رو رفته دوتاي ديه تفاله هاي خيابونين
Then that's what they had in common... they're all bad guys.
س رابطشون يه ـ همشون افراد بدين
Now they're all dead bad guys.
حالا اونا افراد بد مرده ان
Oh, man, you gotta let me do these guys.
ميذاري من اينا رو بزنم
I'm such a moron. I gotta make up for that tit thing.
من مثه کسخلام    من واسش ميميرم
- There's no way. I've been waitin' for this asshole. - Oh, come on.
اره اي نيست. من منتظر کوني بودم    يالا
Come on, man. Give the guy his shot.
يالا   تيرشو حوالش کن
It's the real deal, Roc. Evil men, dead men.
معامله واقعيه روک    مرد بد   مرد مرده
Good shooting...
شليک خوب
shitty shooting.
شليک ند
Plus... we got us a genuine...
بعلاوه ما فرضيه سبک ترور کندي رو اينجا داريم
Kennedy assassination-style bullet theory here.
دو تفن استفاده شده    مرد وسطي
Two guns were used. The guy in the middle...
با هردوش زده شده
was done with both of'em.
اما اين يکي اون کشته شده
Now this guy, he was killed...
فقط با وله هاي تفن اول
with bullets from gun "A" only...
ودومي فقط با تفن دوم
and this guy, gun "B" only.
اما کارشناسا 2 وله از دومي تو ديوار يدا کردن
But ballistics dug two slugs out of the wall from "B"...
کنار جايي که قرباني دوم
over here where the victim was done with "A."
با اولي زده شده
And it's the same thing over here.
و اينجام همونجور
Why the crossover?
را متقاطع؟
That's just fuckin' weird. I have no idea.
بيشرف جادو کرده    نظري ندارم
Jesus, I just can't think anymore.
يا مسيح ذهنم بيشتر جواب نميده
That scene over at the coffee shop today just tapped me out.
امروز صحنه کافي شا تسليمم کرد
What scene?
ه صحنه اي؟
Some guy went nuts over off of Com Ave.
ندنفر تو خيابون کام قاطي ميکنن
Shot three guys to death in a coffee shop, broad daylight, fled the scene.
سه نفرو تو روز روشن ميکشن و فرار ميکنن
- Don't have much on him. - Why wasn't I informed of this?
بيشتر نميدونيم   را من باخبر نشدم؟
They weren't related. The guy used a.38.
اونا ربطي نداشتن   يارو 38 ـ م داشته
- No pennies, totally amateur. - Who were the victims?
بي ارزش  کاملا آماتور   قربانيا کي بودن؟
- A couple of mob peons and a fat fuck bartender. - Oh, isn't that beautiful?
يه زوج ادوي اوباش يه ارسن   زيبا نيست؟
All the lowlifes in quiet city Boston start droppin' dead, and you think it's unrelated!
همه فرومايه ها تو بوستون ميميرن و ميي بي ربطه
Greenly, the day I want the Boston Police to do my thinkin' for me,
رينلي وقتي اومدم ليس بوستون براي درست فکر کردنم
I will have a fucking tag on my toe!
يه نخ دور شستم ييدم
Now get me a squad car and get me over there!
ماشين روهو بده و ببرم اونجا
I want crime scene photos and any witness statements now!
عکساي صحنه جنايت و اظهارات شاهدو ميخوام
Wyatt fuckin' Earp!
عجب صدا خفه کني
It looks like we got us a cowboy. Hmm.
مثل اينکه با يه کابوي طرفيم
[Conner, Murphy] "So we shall flow a river forth to Thee...
ما در رودخانه ات غرقه خواهيم شد
and teeming with souls shall it ever be."
و با ارواح آن بارور خواهيم شت
Hey, hey, man. You guys gotta teach me that prayer.
هي بايد دعا رو بهم ياد بدين
- That's some good shit, man. - Cool it, Roc. It's a family prayer.
جنس عاليه .آروم روک.دعاش خانواديه
- My father's father before him. So that's our shit. - Oh, come on!
در درم.س جنس خودمونه.اوه يالا
[Woman Reporting] The victims were found...
قربانيان در يک تفريحاه
at a local adult entertainment parlor.
جنسي يدا شدند
These murders, coupled with the three suspected mob-related killings...
قاتلان با سه مظنون کشتار تبهکاري مرتبطند
that occurred at this local Boston deli earlier this afternoon,
که هنام عصر در اين نهارخوري روي داد
brings the death toll to six, just today.
که موارد مر را امروز به 6 ميرساند
There is no doubt that all the victims have been criminals.
شکي نيست که همه قربانيان تبهکارند
Perhaps this explains why a public outcry...
شايد اين حمله در ملاء عام موجب
to have these crimes stopped has not been heard.
توقف جرايم شده ـ مشخص نيست
Ah, these two crime scenes are related.
اوه اين دو صحنه جنايت بهم مربوطن
Too many coincidences.
خيلي منطبقن
Same day, five hours apart,
يه روز 5 ساعت فاصله
dead mobsters in both scenes.
انستراي مرده تو هر دو
Now...
حالا
why did he kill the bartender?
را کافه دارو کشته؟
Crime of passion. Just went nuts. He shot everyone in here.
جنايت هوسي. ديوونه شده اون بهرکسي اينجا شليک کرده
- Just ran out of bullets. - Does this look like a friggin' post office to you?
فقط ربار   براتون شبيه يه اداره ست لعنتي نيست؟
This guy came in here with intent.
يارو با قصد مياد اينجا
Maybe he didn't know exactly what he was gonna do, but he had a good idea.
درست نميدونسته ي ميخواد ولي يه ايده خوب داشته
No, the bartender was no fuckin'accident.
نه کافه دار تصادفي نبوده
Well, we didn't need any help on that.
ما دربارش نياز به کمکي نداريم
A lot of people saw it. Nobody's talkin'.
خيليا ديدنش    هيکي يزي نفته
Figures.
قيافه ها
Oh, look.
ناه کنين
Are you guys seeing the pattern here?
الو رو اينجا ديدين؟
We got big questions at both of these crime scenes with no answers.
ما سوالات بزر بدون جوابي براي اين دو صحنه جرم داريم
Why did they kill the guys in the other two booths?
را اونا دو نفر تو اتاقکاي ديرو کشتن؟
Why did they do the bartender?
را کافه دارو کشتن؟
Fuck!
تف
I hate cold crime scenes!
از جرمهاي خونسردانه متنفرم
I'm fucking leaving now.
لعنت الان ميرم بيرون
And do me a favor. Tell me when the next one does,
لطفي بهم بکنين وقتي بعدي مرد بهم بين
'cause these guys are not done yet.
شايد هنوز مرتکبش نشدن
Fuck you.
لعنت بتو
Augustus, I need your help.
آوستوس کمکتو ميخوام
I have a serious problem. I am not screwing around here.
مشکل جدي دارم. اين اطراف نميرخم
I need... Il Duce.
ايلدوه رو ميخوام
The Duke? Huh.
زندان فوق امنيتي هو
What did you do?
دوک؟ ها
Rocco... this package boy...
براي ي؟
he could bring down the whole East Coast.
ميتونه کل ساحل شرقي رو بيکار کنه
If he decides to turn state's evidence,
اه بخواد مدرک ايالتو روکنه
he could take us apart brick by brick.
ميتونه ما رو ازهم باشه
But he's happy, now,
ولي الان خوشحاله
with just killing us one by one.
با کشتن يکي يکيمون
And worse, he's good at it.
وبدتر کارش خوبه
Listen, kid. I hope you understand who you're dealin' with here.
وش کن به اميدوارم بدوني با کي معامله ميکني
This guy is no slouch.
اين مرد آدم بيکفايتي نيست
When I was a boy,
وقتي من يه سر بودم
my papa used to speak of him like he was a ghost.
تو و اا عادتا ازش مثل يه روح صحبت ميکردين
- Move him. - [Guns Cocking]
تکونش بده
[Augustus] Your father and I used him three times in 20 years,
درت و من 3 بار در 20 سال بکار رفتيمش
only when things got totally fucked.
وقتي اوضاع کاملا داغون بود
Whenever we needed one of our own bumped off,
وقتي ميخواستيم يکي از
we'd call this guy in.
خودمونو بکشيم به اون ميفتيم
He had a thing for clippin' wise guys.
يه يزي واسه يره کردن افراد زرن داشت
But only one rule:
ولي فقط يه قانون
No women, no kids.
هي زني  هي به اي
Believe me, kid, you don't want this guy...
بهم اعتماد کن سر  تو اونو نميخواي
unless you are 100% sure you need him.
مه 100% مطمئن باشي
He's a fuckin'monster. But only one thing.
اون يه اعجوبست   ولي فقط يه يز
He's been rottin' in the can the last 25 or 30 years.
اون 25 تا 30 سال اخير تو قوطي بوده
Don't even know if he's still alive or if he's even up to it.
نميدونيم هنوز زندست يا دراومده
There.
اونجا
- Well, there are ways around that. - Yeah. Go find one.
خوب راه داره   آره يداش کن
All right. Let's talk some business here.
باشه  بذار با ندتا تاجر حرف بزنم
I know a sick fuck makes the ones we been doin' look like altar boys.
ميدونم يه مريض لعنتي کلک ديرانو ميکنه که مثل روحانيا بنظر ميرسه
[Rocco] Worst night of my life when I met this guy.
بدترين شب زنديم وقتي ملاقاتش کردم
The guy never says a fuckin' word to me.
مردک هيي بهم نفت
We're drivin'25 minutes,
ـ25 دقيقه رانندي
never a sigh, no throat clearing, nothing.
بدون آه ـ بدون نفس  ـ هيي
Yeah, you're always making great fuckin'sense, you dumb bitch.
آره شماها هميشه صحنه عجيبي ساختين منلا
- I don't care. [Chattering Continues] - [Gunshots]
مهم نيست
[Rocco Continues] His face... blank, man. Just nothin'there.
هره ساکنش مرد هيي اونجا نبود
This guy takes out a whole family...
يارو از س کل يه خانواده برمياد
wife, kids, everyone... like he's ordering a fucking pizza.
زن  به ها  همه  براش مثه سفارش يتزاست
This house is clean.
خونه تميزه
I knew if I didn't keep it together, it was my ass.
ميدونستم اه باهاش نباشم تو ام ميکنه
He has a poker game out back of his place...
يه بازي قمار بيرون داره
with a bunch of wise guys every Saturday.
هر شنبه با يه عده به زرن
Worst day of my life, man.
بدترين روز زنديم مرد
Well, I'm sold.
من فريفته شدم
Don't worry, Roc.
نران نباش روک
We'll do this guy right, and you'll feel a lot better.
درستش ميکنيم و تو حست بهتر ميشه
Okay.
باشه
Here's what happened.
اينجا اتفاق افتاد
They waited in a parked car down the street for the kid to leave.
تو ماشين ارک شده ايين خيابون وايسادن تا به خارج شه
There he goes.
بعد ميره
They came in through the garage.
از اراژ ميان تو
The kid says he leaves it open when he takes his bike out.
به ميه اونو وقتي دورخش تموم شد باز ميذاره
Now they know the wife is the gatekeeper. She knows the code.
ميدونن همسر صاحبخونست  اون رمزو ميدونه
- Hit the numbers, lady. Hit the numbers. - [Muffled Whimpering]
عددارو بزن خانم  عددا رو بزن
- I will kill you! I will kill you! - Don't! Her hands are tied.
ميکشمت  ميکشمت  دستاش باند ييه
Why do I always gotta be on bitch detail?
را من مسوول جنده هام؟
The wife says she doesn't know what happened after she hit the code.
زن ميه نميدونه بعد زدن رمز ي شده
She just remembers going down, but judging from the burn mark on her back,
فقط ايين رفتن يادشه ولي از سوختي شتش
I think what they did was use a stun gun on her.
بنظر اونا يه تفن بيهوشي شتش زدن
Now this guy knows that his friend is coming to the game,
الان اون ميدونه دوستش وارد بازي شده
and they know that this door can only be opened from the inside.
و ميدونن که در فقط از داخل باز ميشه
So they wait. And when that door opens,
س وايميستن. و وقتي در باز ميشه
man...
مرد
nobody's ready for it.
هيکس آماديشو نداره
Panic, devastation.
وحشت  انهدام
This was like shootin' fish in a friggin' barrel.
مثل رتاب ماهي تو يه بشکه داغون
All of'em.
همشون
Now these guys dove under the table.
حالا اونا زير ميز ميرن
The trajectory on the bullet showed that they came from straight across.
جهت شناسي لوله ميه اونا در جهت صاف بودن
So that means one of our shooters dropped to his knees.
که يعني يکيشون رو زانواش افتاده
- Something went wrong right here. - Shit! Shit! He ain't here!
يه يزي جور درنمياد  اه  اه اون اينجا نبوده
Oh, what the fuck you mean, he isn't here?
اوه يعني ي اينجا نيست؟
- I mean he ain't here! - Look again, for fuck's sake!
يعني نيست  دوباره ناه کن لامسبو
I know what the fuck he looks like!
ميدونم لعنتي جوريه
Look behind ya!
شتشو نا
Ah! Son of a...
اه  تخمس
Oh, shit!
اوه  اه
- [Growling] - Shoot this motherfucker!
به مادرجنده شليک کن
No! Fucking let the bloke go!
نه  بذار لعنتي بره
- Let him go! - Fuck! Jesus!
بذار بره   تف  مسيحا
- Now's your chance to earn your stripes, Roc! - He'll fucking get killed!
شانسته که درجه هاتو بيري روک لعنتي ميکشتش
It was your idea to bring him in!
نظر تو بود که اونو وارد کنيم
One of these guys is a real sicko.
يکيشون يه ضعيفه واقعيه
He knew this man. He wanted him to suffer.
ميشناختش  ميخواسته عذاب بکشه
All right, Roc. Now's your chance!
باشه روک شانسته
- You take that man! - I don't wanna die!
تو مييريش   نميخوام بميره
Sick fuck! Sick fuck!
ضعيفه کثافت   ضعيفه کثافت
Sick fuck!
ضعيفه کثيف
- All right then. - Fuck you, fuckin'...
باشه  تف بذاتت
Now take a fuckin' deep breath there, Roc. You did fine.
حالا يه نفس عميق بکش روک  کارت خوب بود
It was nicely done.
خوب تموم شد
They exited out the front door.
از در جلويي درميان
[Smecker] They had no idea what they were in for.
نظري راجع به اونجا بودنشون ندارن
Now they're starin' at six men with guns drawn.
اونا به 6مرد تفندار خيره ميشن
It was a fuckin' ambush.
يه کمين ناجور
This was a fuckin'bomb...
يه بمب ناجور
droppin'on Beaver Cleaverville.
رو بيور کليوروايل افتاده
For a few seconds, this place was Armageddon.
براي ند ثانيه اينجا قيامت ميشه
[Growls] There was a firefight!
جن با ميشه
- [Gun Firing Continues] - [Shouting, Indistinct] You son of a bitch!
تخمس
Murph, are you all right?
مورف  خوبي؟
Motherfucker!
مادرجنده
- Roc, get the fucking bag! - Fuckin'shit! Christ!
روک  کيفو بير  آشغال لعنتي  مسيحا
- Get the blood! Get the blood! - What the fuck was that?
خونو بير خونو بير  اون جورش بود؟
- He shot my fucking finger off! - Roc, what the fuck? Get the fuck out of here!
اون انشتمو روند  روک ته؟ ببرش بيرون
- Motherfucker! - Fucking shit!
مادرجنده   لعنتي
- Get the fucking bag! - My fucking finger!
کيف لعنتي رو بير   انشت لعنتيم
Fucking shit!
بيشرف
What if it was just one guy with six guns?
آيا او فقط يه مرد با 6 تفن بود؟
Why don't you let me do the thinking, huh, genius?
را نميذاري فکر کنم نابغه؟
Hey, what's taking so long with those blood samples?
قدر نمونه خون طول کشيد؟
[Woman] I can't get a good sample.
نميشه نمونه خون بيرم
Oh!
اوه
There's a variable here I'm not seeing.
اينجا بيثباتيه  ناه نميکنم
[Laughing] They used ammonia.
اونا آمونيا داشتن
None of this is any good. Fuck!
هي خوني نيست   تف
You know what that means? Even if we get suspects in the case,
ميدونين يعني ي؟ حتي اه مظنونا رو بيريم
we got nothin', nothin', nothin'!
هيي نداريم  هيي هيي
Fuck! Who the fuck are they?
تف  اونا ديه جورشن؟
I've never seen any fucking thing like this in my fucking life!
تو تمام زنديم اين رقمشو نديده بودم
Who the fuck are they?
اونا ه جورشن؟
Who the fuck was he, Rocco? I know you fucking know, so don't even start.
کي بود روک   ميدوني س شروع نکن
Fuck you! I told you I never saw him before!
تف بذاتت  فتم قبلا نديدمش
Well, he sure as fuck knew you!
اون حتما ميشناستت کثافت
Fuck you! Fuck you both!
تف بذاتت  تف بهردوتون
- [All Arguing] - Yeah? Don't start lying to us now!
آره؟ بهمون دروغ نو
We're fuckin' three amateurs here!
ما 3 تا آماتور لعنتي اينجاييم
I'm confident that their investigation will end...
مطمئنم تحقيقشون تموم ميشه
in the apprehension of the suspects.
درباره دستيري مظنونا
- Fuckin' hell. - What? What, that guy?
لعنتي  ي؟  اون مرد ي؟
That's the guy that got us off the hook with the Checkov thing.
همونيه که مارو تو جريان کوف يرانداخت
- And he's one smart man. - They got nothin'.
مرد باهوشيه   اونا هيي ندارن
Well, this guy is very sharp. If he hasn't figured us out yet, he will.
خيلي زرنه  بالاخره يدامون ميکنه
- You bet your ass he will. - Well, I'd say that makes him a lia-fuckin'-bility.
به کونت قسم که ميتونه  براي لامسب تعهد داره
- He isn't to be touched. - He's a good man.
اون لمس نشده   مرد خوبيه
Okay, whatever.
خوب هري
No, that's all wrong. David Della...
همش غلطه  ديويد دلا روکو
I missed it.
مش کردم
Paul, you've already had quite a bit. Are you sure you wanna...
اول تو يه ذره داشتي  مطمئني ميخواي
- Just pour the drink, you fairy fuck. - [Gasping]
شربتو بريز  ساحره بيشرف
Whew! I smell you.
وو  بوت ميکنم
Hey, Murph.
هي مورف
This early mornin' church shit's gotta go.
صبح زود ميخواي بري کليساي لامسب
We have to go in the mornin'. We're on the lam now, you know.
بايد صبح بريم  ميدوني ما فراري ايم
Hey.
هي
[Whispering] You're gonna do what I say, got it?
همونيکه فتمو بکن رفتي؟
- Yes. - I'm sorry you're gonna have to see this.
بله  بايد ببينيش
- Don't look at me. - I didn't see any...
بهم ناه نکن   هيي نميبينم
Shut up. Shut the fuck up.
خفه  خفه کثافت
[Priest] Don't do this, my son.
نکن  سرم
Have you no fear of God?
ترسي از خدا نداري؟
That's who I'm doin' this for. Now open the fuckin' thing, Father.
اينکارو واسه اون ميکنم  لامسبو باز کن در
Father, I'll do you right here.
در ميخوام الان انجام بدي
God have mercy on my soul.
خدا روحمو رحمت ميکنه
You little fuck, let him go or I'll drop you right fuckin' now.
لامسب بذار بره يا ميکونم بيشرف
Okay, just calm down. He could hurt us, brother.
خوب آروم  ميتونه زخميمون کنه برادر
- He could ruin the whole thing. - You let him go...
ميتونه همه رو داغون کنه   بذار بره
or I will deliver you right fucking here!
يا همين الان حوالت ميکنم
You won't do it. You won't, Conner. You love me, man.
نميکني  نميکني کانر   دوستم داري مرد
- I swear to fuckin'... - Hello. You there?
به لامسب قسم که...  سلام اونجايي؟
Y-Yes, my son.
آره سرم
[Whispering] Do your thing, Father. Don't fuck this up.
کارتو بکن در  بشاش به اين
- How long since your last confession? - Christ.
آخرين اعترافت کي بود؟   مسيحا
I've never confessed.
هرز اعتراف نکردم
I come here for advice,
اينجا واسه نصيحت ميام
not "slalvation."
نه رستاري
Why have you come to a church for counsel if you're not religious?
مذهبي که نيستي را واسه اندرز کليسا مياي؟
It's ethics.
اخلاقه
I put evil men behind bars,
اشرارو شت ميله ها ميندازم
but the law has miles of red tape and loopholes...
ولي قانون هزاران دن و فن داره
for these cocksuckers to slip through.
تا اين خايه مالا بريزن
I found... out there are these two guys...
فهميدم   2 نفرن
who fix the situation with an iron fist...
که وضعيتو با مشت آهني سفت کردن
as if they had God's permission.
انار که اجازه خدا رو داشتن
God's permission? God doesn't grant...
اجازه خدا؟  خدا اجازه نميده
In this day and age,
تو اين روزار
I believe what they do is necessary.
معتقدم کارشون ضروريه
I feel it is correct.
حس ميکنم درسته
A soul is what gives us feelings.
روحيه که بما احساس ميده
It's like a conduit...
مثل معبري
through which the Lord speaks to us.
که خدا باهامون حرف ميزنه
You felt your answers would be here...
بنظرت اينجا اسخت
in the house of the Lord today.
امروز در مامن خداست
And you feel... these men are necessary.
و بنظرت ... اونا لازمن
So the Lord has spoken to you twice today.
س خدا دوبار بهت فته
Has He now? [Scoffs]
الان داره؟
You are the one who came into this church speaking about beliefs and feelings.
تنها کسيکه راجع به عقايد و احساسات اينجا حرف زده تويي
Is it so hard to believe that God has brought you here?
سخته باور کني خدا اينجا بهت نازل شده؟
I guess not.
نميدونم
It's very easy to be sarcastic about religion.
تمسخر دين برات راحته
But it's much more difficult...
ولي سخت ترش
to take a stand. [Sighs]
داشتن ايداريه
I wanna stand for what I believe in, Father.
من در راه ايمانم ايدارم در
First you have to know what your beliefs are.
بايد بدوني عقايدت يه؟
I believe that these young men are right.
معتقدم کار اين جوونا درسته
- You know them personally? - Yes.
شخصا ميشناسيشون؟    بله
Would they ever harm an innocent person, for any reason?
شخص بيناهي رو بيدليل کشتن؟
No. They would never do that.
نه   هرز
Well, the two Irish guys wouldn't.
نه   2تا ايرلنديه نه
The Italian guy, he might. He's kind of an idiot.
ايتالياييه ممکنه  يجورايي ابلهه
I'm beginning to see.
دارم ميفهمم
All the things I wish I could do,
هر ي اميدوار بودمو
these guys are doing.
اينا انجام ميدن
W-W-What should I do?
يکار کنم؟
Because I am a man...
ون من کسي ام
who's supposed to uphold the law.
که قراره حامي قانون باشه
The laws of God... are higher...
قوانين خدا...برترن
than the laws... of man.
از قوانين...انسان
Yes, l-I was thinking that too. No, no. I was feeling it.
منم بهمين معتقدم    نه حسم اينه
All I needed was to hear you say it.
هري ميخواستمو از تو شنيدم
Amen. I will help them.
آمين.کمکشون ميکنم
- Forgive me, Father. - Thank you, Father.
منو ببخش در   تشکر در
Whatever.
بهرحال
Amen. Good-bye.
آمين   خداحافظ
[Rocco] Now listen. Um, "dominus ominus,"you know.
وش کن   شانس بد   ميدوني
And remember, you're bound. You can't talk to anyone about this. No one.
تحت نظري  بهيکي راجع به اين نو  هيکي
- Just get out of the church. - Okay.
از کليسا ورتو م کن   باشه
Just get out of the church!
از کليسا م شو
The Lord works in mysterious ways.
خدا کاراش سريه
What the fuck's that supposed to mean?
لامسب ه معني ميده؟
- That's all you can give me? - The light hit the side of his face.
اينه همه اونيکه بهم ميدي؟ نور سمت صورتش زده
Looked like he had a gray beard. Maybe late '50s, early '60s.
مثکه ريشش خاکستريه   ديرش 50  زودش 60
So you're telling me it was one guy with six guns,
ميي يکي بوده با 6 تفن
and he was a senior freakin' citizen?
و يه جنتلمن عوضي بوده
Yeah, and it's better if we find this man before he finds us again.
بهتره زودتر يداش کنيم
I'll see what I can do. How do I get in touch with you?
ميدونم يکار کنم   طور باهات درتماس باشم؟
We'll hit Pappa Joe tonight, right in the comfort of his own home.
امشب اا جو رو ميزنيم  درحال استراحت خونيش
We're gonna move on to New York. It's just...
ميخوايم بريم نيويورک   همين
- It's getting a bit hot for us here. - Be careful.
اينجا خيلي واسمون داغه   مواظب باشين
All right. Call you tonight, afterwards.
باشه  بعدا تماس مييريم
- It feels like it's still there. - Yeah, but it's not.
حس ميشه هنوز اينجاست   نه نيست
[Augustus] I don't know who he is. Nobody does.
نميدونم اون کيه  هيکي نميدونه
The Duke's a fuckin'Houdini. He does a disappearin'act.
دوک يه مرتاض بيشرفه کارش نايداست
What did he bring him in for?
کي اونو وارد کرده؟
Well, he needs an outsider. This Rocco kid is smart.
ما يه خارجي ميخوايم روکو باهوشه
He knows everyone. He'd spot our hitters a mile away.
همه رو ميشناسه اون مايلها دورتر قصدمونو ميخونه
Just for him... the package boy?
فقط واسه سر اکتي
He's the one shootin' up all his guys, right? He's scared of the kid.
اون همه رو ترور کرد؟   اون از سره ترسيده
- Said he's good. He's got every gun in the city up there. - Up where?
فتي خوبه  اون همه تفنا رو راه انداخته   کجا؟
Up at his house. I don't know what's going on,
تو خونش راه انداخته  نميدونم ي ميشه
but I know it's gotta have something to do with this kid.
ميخواد به سره يه درس حسابي بده
Oh, fuck!
بيشرف
We got 'em. They tried to get in through the basement.
ميخوان از زيرزمين برن
- How many? - Three.
ندتان؟   3
[Man] Where you goin', huh? Where the fuck you goin', huh?
يکار ميکنين ها؟   ه هي ميخورين؟
I'm fuckin' talkin' to you, motherfucker!
مثلا دارم حرف ميزنم مادرجنده
- Fuck you! - Shut up!
تف بذاتت   خفه
Shh! Shh. Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
.....
Sit up.
محکم باش
You have some answers for me, no?
جواب برامون داري نه؟
Yeah. Fuck you.
تف بذاتت
Roc! Roc, look at me!
روک  نام کن
- [Indistinct Shouting] - Roc! - [Gunshot]
روک
[Screaming] Shit!
تف
- Roc! Roc, you'll be fine! - [Screaming Continues]
روک خوب ميشي
- Roc!
روک
Okay. What do you boys think?
خوب نظرتون يه؟
- These guys are tough. - Fuckin'-A, right.
اينا مقاومن لامسبا
- Ain't no fuckin' way they're gonna talk. - I know Rocco.
هي جور حرف نميزنن   روکو رو ميشناسم
He ain't smart enough for this shit. Those other guys are the brains.
اون اينجا ديه باهوش نيست اوناي ديه مخن
- He's just a player. - He's a punk.
اون فقط يه هنريشست  وکه
There's only one thing to do.
يکار ديه مونده
God! No!
خدايا نه
- Roc! Roc! No! - [Indistinct Shouting]
روک روک نه
Roc! Roc!
روک
- [Murphy Whimpering] - No!
نه
No! Roc!
نه روک
Roc!
روک
You can't stop! You get out of here. Don't ever stop.
نبايد توقف کنين  برين بيرون  هرز توقف نکنين
Roc! No!
روک  نه
No! Roc!
نه  روک
- You motherfucker! - [Crying]
مادرجنده
Yeah! I'm gonna kill them!
ميخوام بکشمشون
- [Man] Hey, boss. - Yeah, Chappy?
رئيس   بله اي؟
I don't mean no disrespect, but I think we're forgettin' something here.
بي احترامي نميکنم ولي يه يزي يادمون رفته
This II Duce's a fuckin' animal. He's gonna stop when someone dies.
ايلدوه يه حيوون درندست واينميسته تا کسي بميره
I guarantee you right now, he thinks this thing is on.
مطمئنا حق با تويه بنظرش اين رونده بازه
- What? - [Italian Continues]
ي؟
If this guy still thinks the job is on,
اه بنظرش رونده بازه
motherfucker is in the bushes right now.
الان مادرجنده تو هل افتاده
I am going. You four... stay here...
ميرم   شما 4 تا  بمونين
and deal with it.
و حلش کنين
[Shouts] Do it!
يالا
- Just one fuckin' guy. - Fuck you, Geno.
فقط يه آشعال   تف بتو ژنو
- What's the big fuckin' deal? - Do it!
مشکل اصلي يه؟   يالا
I'm going back downstairs and workin' on these pricks.
من ميرم ايين حواسم به سوراخاست
- What the fuck? - [Grunting]
ه وضعيه؟
Hey.
هي
Joey Bevo sent me over...
جووي بيوو منو فرستاده
as entertainment.
واسه تفريح
Sorry, baby. Tonight ain't the night for this shit.
امشب واسه کثافت خوب نيست عزيزم
It's really hittin' the fan in there, you know what I'm sayin'?
اونجا واقعا ميسبه  ميدوني؟
Fuckin' Bevo's great, man. He's always sendin' us primo box.
لامسب بيوو  واسمون هميشه کادو ميفرسته
All right. Let's go.
خوب  بريم
[Geno Whispering] Come here.
بيا اينجا
- What the fuck are you doing? - Come on, man.
ه غلطي ميکردي؟   بيا مرد
I haven't been laid in a week. It'll take five minutes.
يه هفته حال نکردم   نج دقيقه اي تمومه
Hurry up!
يالا
Oh, baby. Oh, come to Mama.
بيا بغل مامان
- You're a dirty girl. No. - Come to Mama. Oh, come to Mama. Oh.
دختره کثيف  نه   بيا بغل مامان  بيا
- You wanna ride the champ? - Yeah, baby.
ميخواي نشخوار کني؟    حتما عزيزم
- All right. All right. Let's do it, man. Ringside. - Big, strong man.
خوب يالا مرد وقت کشتيه  هيکل
- Come on, baby. - Yeah, that's right. You want a little shot at the title?
يالا جير  يه تير شت قبالت ميخواي؟
I'll give you a shot at the title right here...
الان يه تير حوالت ميکنم
- What the fuck? - [Yelling]
ه افتضاحي؟
Too far.
خيلي بعيد
It's on now.
حالا درسته
Hey, babe. What's it, two for one?
هي جير يه دو تا براي يکي؟
[Together] "And shepherds we shall be...
و اي شبان ما از آن
"for Thee, my Lord, for Thee.
توييم خدايا از آن تو
- Power hath descended forth from Thy ha..." - [Guns Click]
قدرت در دستان توست
"That our feet may swiftly carry out Thy command.
اهايمان بسرعت تحت فرمانت ميشوند
"We will flow a river forth unto Thee,
در رودخانه ات غرقه ميشويم
and teeming with souls shall it ever be."
و از روحهايش باروريم
Standing trial today for the third time in two years...
امروز سومين برزاري محاکمه در 2 سال
is infamous Mafia don Pappa Joe Yakavetta.
براي اا جو رهبر بدنام مافيا
Yakavetta takes the stand to defend himself...
ياکاوتا در حال دفاع است
against allegations of his involvement...
دربرابر اتهام دخالت در
in the ordered killings of no less than 17 men.
کشتار حداقل 17 نفر
The state's case against him relies heavily on circumstantial evidence...
رونده او داراي مدارک محکمي است
and a third acquittal has already been predicted.
و سومين حکم برائتش آماده ميباشد
[Il Duce] Never shall innocent blood be shed.
هرز خون بيناهي نبايد بريزد
Yet, the blood of the wicked...
اکنون خون شيطان
shall flow like a river.
بايد مانند رودي جاري شود
The three shall spread their blackened wings...
سه نفر بايد بالهاي کثيفشان را بينند
and be the vengeful, striking hammer of God.
و انتقام بيرند  تبر کوبنده خداوند
Ah, I was with my mother.
با برادرم بودم
We were at the Genovese... the butcher...
ما تو قصابي جنوويسه بوديم
- because on Thursdays she makes a gnocchi for... - [Laughing]
ون 3شنبه ها يه فيله براي
- [Italian] - [Judge] Mr. Yakavetta,
ياکاوتا درست ميکرديم
you will demonstrate order in my courtroom.
سفارشو در داداه من ثابت کنين
- Counsel, proceed. - Look at his charisma.
مشورت درجريانه  به جذبه اش دقت کن
- He's the next John Gotti. - He'll walk,
جان وتي بعديه   اون راحته
even with all this evidence.
عليرغم تمامي مدارک
Look, all of Yakavetta's people are on the left.
فاميل ياکاوتا همي سمت ن
All the families of the men he's killed are on the right.
خانواده کسايي که کشته سمت راستن
Everyone wants some justice.
همه خواهان عدالتن
- I don't know where I was. - Look at him.
نميدونم کجا بودم   ناش کن
He doesn't have a care in the world.
هيي تو دنيا براش مهم نيست
He's gonna walk. [Laughing]
ميخواد ردش کنه
- [Indistinct Shouting] - You, to the back!
تو برو عقب
Shut the fucking camera!
دوربين لامسبو ببند
Up top, drop your guns! One at a time! Now! Drop it!
بالا تفنارو بندازين همزمان  يالا
- Come here. - Where are you taking me?
بيا اينجا   کجا منو ميبري؟
- What are you doing? What are you doing? - Shut the fuck up!
کجا ميري؟ يکار ميکني؟   خفه شو
Get to the back!
برو عقب
You people have been chosen...
شماها منتخبين
to reveal our existence to the world!
براي افشاي موجوديت ما به دنيا
You will witness what happens here today,
شما شاهدين امروز ي ميشه
and you will tell of it later.
وشما بعدا ازش ياد ميکنين
All eyes to the front.
همه شما باز
- Now is a good time to fucking... - Shut your fuckin' mouth!
وقت خوبي براي لعنتيه  دهن التو ببند
You must watch, dear.
بايد ببيني عزيز
It'll all be over soon.
بزودي تموم ميشه
Get down, get down, get down!
ايين  ايين
Now you will receive us!
شما ما رو درک ميکنين
We do not ask for your poor or your hungry!
از فقر يا رسنيتون نميرسيم
We do not want your tired and sick!
ما ناراحتي و بيماري شما رو نميخوايم
- It is your corrupt we claim. - It is your evil that will be sought by us!
ادعامون فساد شماست  ما يير شرارت شماييم
With every breath, we shall hunt them down.
هر لحظه شکارشون ميکنيم
Each day we will spill their blood...
هميشه خونشونو ميريزيم
till it rains down from the skies!
تا از آسمون خون بباره
Do not kill, do not rape, do not steal.
نکشين تجاوز نکنين دزدي نکنين
These are principles which every man of every faith can embrace!
اين اصولو هر کسي و هر ديني ميذيره
These are not polite suggestions! These are cores of behavior,
مودبانه نيستن   اينا رموز رفتارن
and those of you that ignore them will pay the dearest cost!
و کوتاهي از اونها براتون خيلي رونه
There are varying degrees of evil.
درجات وناوني از شر هست
We urge you lesser forms of filth not to push the bounds and cross over...
اصرار ما بر فساد کمتره نه اجباري و نه ذشت از
into true corruption, into our domain.
فساد واقعي  در قلمرو ما
For if you do, one day you will look behind you...
روزيکه انجامش بدين شتتونو ناه کنين
and you will see we three.
و ما 3 تا رو ببينين
And on that day, you will reap it!
و اونروز درکش ميکنين
And we will send you to whatever god you wish.
و هر ي خدا بخواد براتون ميفرستيم
"And shepherds we will be, for Thee, my Lord, for Thee.
و شبان ما از آن توييم سرورم از آن تو
"Power hath descended forth from Thy hand...
قدرت در دستان توست
- [Cursing In Italian] - "That our feet may swiftly carry out Thy command.
و اهايمان بسرعت تحت فرمانت ميشوند
"So we shall flow a river forth to Thee,
س در رودخانه ات شناوريم
and teeming with souls shall it ever be."
و با ارواح آن بارور ميشويم
[Reporter] Did you see what happened?
ديدي ي شد؟
- [Crying] Yes, I was there. - [Sirens Wailing]
آره اونجا بودم
How far are we going to take this?
تا کجا ادامش ميديم در؟
The question is not how far.
نميشه فت تا کجا
The question is, do you possess the constitution,
بايد فت سرشتي رو دارين
the depth of faith,
عمق ايمان
to go as far as is needed?
براي طي طريق؟
After the astonishing display of vigilantism...
س از نمايش حيرت انيز بيداري
during the Yakavetta trial yesterday,
طي داداه ياکاوتا
the largest manhunt in recent memory is being undertaken...
بزرترين مجازات تبهکاري تحت يرده
to capture three men the media have dubbed "the Saints."
ـ3 مرديه که رسانه ها اونها را  ـ رهيزکاران ـ ناميدند
This reporter went out to the street to find out what you thought about these three.
زارشر ما در بيرون از شما درباره اين 3 ميرسه
Somebody can just go out, get a gun and shoot somebody...
هرکي ميتونه بره بيرون و يکي رو با تفن بکشه
because they feel they're doing some good in the world?
ون حس کردن کارشون خوبه؟
- No comment. - Making the world a safer place. - Are you kidding?
بي نظرم ساختن دنيايي امنتر  دستم انداختين؟
- They're killing for good and only the people who kill. - Listen to yourself.
کشتن براي خوبي فقط مردم ميميرن بوجدانت رجوع کن
This is gonna create something so much worse.
اينجوري همه ي بدتر ميشه
- I don't think so at all. - Well, I think you're just naive then.
نظر من اين نيست  بنظرم تو ساده لوحي
I love the Saints, man. They doin' a great job.
رهيزکارانو دوست دارم   کارشون عاليه
Keep it goin', man. Get these murderers off the streets.
ادامه بدين  قاتلا رو از خيابونا جمع کنين
They're not out there just killing for fame.
اونا نميکشن مه واسه شهرت
- They just wanna be famous. - They should be in every major city.
ميخوان مشهور شن  تو هر شهر بزري هستن
- Every major city. - These guys are playing God.
هر شهر بزي   دارن رل خدا رو بازي ميکنن
This whole religious twist. Who do they think they are?
مذهبشون تاب ورداشته  فکر ميکنن کين؟
I believe in capital punishment. If they let me, I'd pull the switch.
تاوان سرمايه ست  اه بذارن سوئيو ميکشم
Get 'em all! Kill 'em all!
همشونو بزنين  همشونو بکشين
I'm all for it. [Beep] them [Beep].
من کلا براشم   اونا
The more people they kill, the better it is for everybody. That's what they get...
بيشتر که بکشن براي همه بهتره  کارشون همينه
No, do not do that, Laquelle, because you don't even know!
نه لاکوئل تو اصلا نميفهمي
- Sign me up, man. - Sign me up. All right?
موافقم مرد  موافقم ها؟
- Where can I sign up? - Who are they to be judge and jury? V
کجا ميتونم موافقت کنم؟ اونا براي کي قاضين؟
- No. What if your mom sees? - No comment.
نه نظر مادرت ي ميشه؟     بدون نظر
- I'm afraid for myself.
بدون نظر    واسه خودم نرانم
I'm afraid for my kids. I'm afraid to walk down the street.
نرانم واسه به هام   ميترسم خيابون برم
I can't even believe you're saying that. That's crazy.
باورم نميشه ي ميين   ديوونيه
When did you turn into such a sissy?
کي دخترت کردن؟
- I think they just get off on killing people. - Well, I have no comment.
فقط کشتن مردمو ترک کنن   بدون نظر
- No comment on that, dear. - I have nothing to say. Thanks.
نظري ندارم عزيز   هيي نميم  تشکر
All this hoopla with the media. You guys are making it worse right now.
هياهوي رسانه اي    دارين بدترش ميکنين
You're giving them the power.
دارين قدرت بهشون ميدين
By sticking that in my face, you're giving the Saints power.
با سبيدن به صورتم    مقدسانو قوي ميکنين
- I don't wanna talk about it. - I really don't wanna talk about that.
نميخوام دربارش صحبت کنم   اصلا نميخوام
You walk into some kid's bedroom and it's gonna be there.
اون تو اتاق خواب به ها هم هست
You have Batman, Superman and these Saints.
بتمن دارين سورمن دارين اينم رهيزکاران
Are you losing any sleep, honey?
خوابت کم شده عسل؟
- 'Cause you know what? I'm certainly not. - No comment.
ييزايي فهميدي؟  من بهيوجه  نظري ندارم
- Don't talk to them. - They're damn good. They're right!
باهاشون حرف نزن  خيلي خوبن  کارشون درسته
I'm ready to [Beep] My [Beep] on.
حاضرم
Okay? I'm ready to get busy too.
باشه؟ منم حاضرم دست بکار شم
You know, I'm ready to get busy.
ميدوني   منم حاضرم دست بکار شم